DM: So Oren, does Wellby want to be a dragon in the next combat?
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Speaking of.
Wellby: Who wants to be a dragon just like to see what's that like?
Delwath: I mean, do, do we have an extra day?
Unknown: What do you mean?
Delwath: Delwath, I took as my next level spell True Polymorph.
Delwath: I can turn anything into a dragon.
Unknown: Yeah. Well, I think, I think just-
Delwath: As long as they're a 20th level character.
Unknown: [laughs] I can turn anything-
Kenzo: I think be- I think before the campaign ends-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, definitely
Kenzo: ... yeah, we should all experience being a dragon.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like, that's like pretty sick, you know?
Wellby: The potential for practical jokes really increases with True Polymorph.
Unknown: Right. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Like, "Oh, sorry, something went wrong."
Delwath: Or, "Oh, shit, what has happened?"
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Kong, do you wanna record a backup race menu too?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: In case mine doesn't catch everything too.
Unknown: For sure.
DM: Oh, and where did... Where did the speakers go?
Unknown: I
Unknown: don't know.
Delwath: Actually, that's making me think. Is there any dragon that is resistant to-
Unknown: Ooze
Delwath: ... or immune to ooze, immune to acid damage?
Wellby: Uh, black dragons.
DM: Black dragons and possibly
Unknown: copper or bronze.
Delwath: I mean, but black dragons also do acid damage.
DM: Yeah. That's, that's the downside to dragons is-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... they all are resistant to the damage they do.
DM: So if you wanna be resistant to...
Unknown: Which actually,
DM: theoretically pretty good for Seeker
DM: because you could... Seeker could turn into a dragon resistant to acid damage and then just cast spells instead of-
Unknown: Oh
Unknown: ... using the breath weapon.
Unknown: That makes sense.
Seeker: So what's a dragon resistant to acid damage?
Delwath: Um, a copper dragon is not only resistant to acid damage, it's immune to acid damage.
Unknown: That's even better.
Delwath: It's only challenge 14, but...
DM: But if you're just gonna be casting spells, does it matter?
Unknown: It has a...
Delwath: It can replace one, it, it has a slowing breath.
Seeker: Like, what are the, Ooze's minions gonna look like?
Seeker: We have no idea what we're walking into, as always.
Delwath: I mean, a copper dragon is not crazy.
Unknown: What's the-
Delwath: Oh, man. An ancient copper dragon is one-
Unknown: It's CR 21.
Delwath: It's CR 21. It's one too high.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Seeker is, like, not interested in very many-
DM: Yeah, Seeker's done the dragon thing and...
Unknown: Seeker's not.
Kenzo: So give me some tra- dragon, uh, trauma bonding, Seeker.
Wellby: Seeker's fully 100%
Delwath: But, but like Kenzo-
DM: Kenzo wasn't traumatic at all.
Unknown: ... Kenzo was successful.
Kenzo: Oh, no, Kenzo loved that shit. No, it was great.
Wellby: T for Seeker.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Um, T, T is short for something.
Wellby: It's a middle name.
Kenzo: Little T Seeker. [laughs] Um, somebody had, like, a USB-C charger over here.
Unknown: That, that was mine.
Unknown: That's mine.
Unknown: Oh, here. Here, Kong.
Delwath: Do you need a USB-C?
DM: My, my computer is fully charged.
Delwath: I also, I have one that I'm not using if you guys need more.
Kenzo: Yeah, maybe just have one out to charge various things.
Seeker: Uh, I think I have one.
Seeker: Are any of the dairy products known good, like milks or cream?
DM: All of the dairy products should be known good.
Wellby: The half & half I just opened this morning.
Wellby: That's terrible.
Unknown: It's the purple one here?
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: I'm just trying to maximize my energy.
Kenzo: Mike, Mike, do you have a, do you have a USB-C charger?
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I might actually not. Now that I'm thinking about it, I might not.
Delwath: Oh, no worries about it. Oh, no, don't worry
Kenzo: about it. No big deal.
Unknown: Ugh.
Unknown: Uh.
Kenzo: Man, this is so awesome.
Kenzo: I love that we do this every year.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: It is
Kenzo: really, it's really,
Kenzo: it's super fantastic. Oh, perfect.
Unknown: Thank you.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Delwath: It's my fancy little travel charger.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: I got sick of-
Unknown: I think there's a plug...
Delwath: I got sick of hotel rooms that did not have enough plugs to charge my...
Unknown: Sweet.
Delwath: I mean, a copper dragon, its breath weapon's, it has a slowing breath
Unknown: which recharges.
Delwath: Its rend does acid damage, but that's, who cares?
Unknown: Copper dragon?
Delwath: Copper dragon.
Seeker: Sounds pretty cool.
Unknown: And-
Seeker: Is there anything that's not a copper dragon or not a dragon that is also immune to acid damage?
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: let's see. Can I search?
Unknown: Yeah, you can search fire.
Delwath: Damage immunity, acid.
Unknown: Challenge.
Seeker: Oh, like that poison troll or whatever
Seeker: we trapped one time.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Is that still in the Mirror, Mirror-
DM: No, the poison troll destroyed-
Unknown: We deployed it
Unknown: ... the vampires.
Unknown: We deployed it.
DM: We deployed it. The vampires.
Delwath: Um, let's see. A black dragon is also
Delwath: immune to acid.
Kenzo: Eric, did you do this with your mind?
Seeker: [laughs] I did it unintentionally in my mind.
Delwath: It's, um, the black dragon is not as good as a copper dragon, I don't think.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: let's see. Hold on. I got a filter on.
Unknown: A leviathan.
Unknown: I'm down for that.
Unknown: Gargantuan elemental.
Unknown: Ooh, a, a leviathan.
Unknown: Gigantic serpent.
Unknown: A roar.
DM: Immune to acid and poison.
Unknown: Yeah, this is the one.
DM: Your, but your d- your attacks do am- acid damage too.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: I mean-
Seeker: But if I can cast spells
Unknown: ... you can cast spells, yeah.
Delwath: And a tidal wave Is that not a compatible CR?
DM: Yes, CR20. [coughs] Three legendary resistances.
DM: If you take 50 or more cold damage in a single turn, you partially freeze.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And your attacks-
Delwath: Actually has resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing.
Delwath: Immunity to acid and poison.
DM: But from non-magical attacks.
Unknown: Yeah, that's, that will be useless.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: Uh, ex- immune to exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, and stunned.
Unknown: It's pretty good.
DM: Yeah, that is pretty good.
Unknown: It's like a giant...
Delwath: It's basically a giant water elemental.
DM: Giant sea serpent.
Delwath: No, it's like a water elemental, right?
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: A sea slug?
DM: Sea serpent.
Wellby: Oh. [laughs] Transforming into it on land, it just looks [laughs] sloppier.
DM: Well, it's, it's...
DM: Yeah, it has a move speed of 40.
DM: It has a swim speed of 120.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: But 40 isn't terrible.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: 14 to hit, reach 20, one target.
Seeker: How, wait, how big is gargantuan?
Unknown: Gargantuan is-
DM: 20 foot by 20 foot.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah, I think that's-
DM: Oh. [laughs]
Unknown: I have an idea.
Seeker: Okay, if you turn into that... Yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm heading that direction.
Unknown: [laughs] That's, that
Delwath: is a pretty good... I don't see...
Delwath: I don't see m- I mean, a copper dragon also has a lot of
Unknown: things that might be good.
Seeker: However, I'll do this so long as nobody hits it.
DM: You can use giant's strength.
Kenzo: Oh, perfect. [laughs] Now I can crouch to the right size.
DM: Yeah, that's close enough to the right size.
Unknown: Only thing is, I don't know if it's a four by four.
DM: Yeah. [coughs]
Delwath: Yeah, that's pretty much...
Delwath: Co- a copper dragon or a leviathan are your pretty much your...
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [clears throat]
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Schwartz, if you could make something that we can pose this all on, that would be great.
Unknown: So everything on...
Wellby: Yeah, I think I'm gonna do it with, like, a, like, a meeting table in the middle and then a little pool and, like, a living wall of, like, trees and plants and stuff coming out of it.
Delwath: Oh my God. Oh, you know what's pretty good?
Delwath: An ancient brass dragon.
Wellby: Mm.
Delwath: CR20.
Delwath: It makes... It has a sleep breath.
Unknown: That
Delwath: each creature in a 90-foot cone, failure of the target has the incapacitated condition until the end of its next turn, at which point it repeats the save.
Kenzo: Second failure, it's unconscious for 10 minutes.
Delwath: It wakes up if you do damage, but...
Unknown: It has fire breath.
Kenzo: So Schwartz, you, like, visualize the whole thing-
Wellby: Yep
Seeker: ... get, like, 30 parts for making it-
DM: Oh, thank you
Seeker: ... and then build it, and then do that again?
DM: I'll take two.
Seeker: Yeah. I'm just watching you and thinking, like, how did you just-
Wellby: I don't know.
Unknown: Love that.
Wellby: Hm? Schwartz?
Wellby: Oh, no thanks.
Wellby: Yeah, it's visualizing, but it's not,
Wellby: it's not actually visualizing the end product.
Wellby: It's more like
Wellby: visualizing the concept of the end product.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Wellby: And then, like, building towards it, and in the building towards it, you're actually creating the thing, like...
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: It feels more like I'm visuali- like-
Seeker: You have like a little sketch or like one-
Wellby: ... visualizing. Yeah, or almost like a heuristic for how to go about-
Unknown: Oh
Wellby: ... moving through the process.
Unknown: Huh.
Wellby: Like, I know I'm gonna use these kind of studs to build on, to attach greens, and then-
Seeker: Oh, it's techniques that you're combining.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: And then I'm gonna layer it, so.
Unknown: Oh, cool.
Wellby: Yeah. It's not actually visualizing the,
Wellby: like, the final thing in all its detail.
Seeker: I'm just trying to... Like I- I have
Seeker: Technic stuff out. Izzy and I played with it a little bit.
Unknown: I'm like,
Seeker: it's, it helps you see, like, wow, there's a lot of implicit knowledge that goes into this.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Like, you, she puts axles in things, and then they fall out again.
Seeker: Oh, it needs to be secured on both ends.
Unknown: Like, there's a-
Wellby: Yeah
Seeker: ... way of thinking about-
Wellby: Right
Unknown: ... and having parts.
Wellby: Yes. Yes.
DM: Did everybody level up to level 20?
Unknown: Learn that. No.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: I just did you, Colin.
Unknown: Oh, thank you.
Wellby: Yeah, and like, do you have to learn that actively?
Wellby: Like, do you,
Wellby: can you only learn it by doing things?
DM: Wow.
Wellby: I'm like-
DM: That's pretty strong. Your, your dex is now 25.
DM: You have a plus seven dexterity.
DM: Your wisdom is 22.
DM: You have a plus six.
Delwath: That makes your base AC is 24 plus dex.
DM: Your AC is 24.
Wellby: Whoa.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Unhittable.
DM: You d- you have plus 15 to hit with the staff and plus 13 with your fists.
Wellby: Holy shit.
Delwath: You know what's a pretty good-
DM: And your save DC for your aura strikes is now 20
Unknown: Why did that jump up so much?
DM: 'Cause your level 20 monk ability-
Unknown: Yeah, plus four
DM: ... is a plus four to wisdom and plus four to dex.
Seeker: Holy butt.
Delwath: That's what I see. You know what's a good creature?
Unknown: I set myself to 20.
Delwath: I might, I might ex- I might shape-shift.
Delwath: An animal lord.
Unknown: Animal lord?
Delwath: An animal lord. It's a celestial.
Delwath: It has four legendary resistances.
Kenzo: I wonder if there's, like, build and shape, try it and take a card for it.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: it makes two attacks plus-
Unknown: Take a card for it
Unknown: ... its attack is amazing.
Kenzo: Like, oh, that's not super efficient.
Unknown: 46.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: Just trying to figure out
Delwath: ... but it can summon an animal spirit.
Kenzo: You should give a guest lecture in, uh, Eric's, uh, learning creative learning class.
Unknown: [laughs] Like, something
Unknown: [laughs] Or just how you
Wellby: I feel like my life would be like, "Well, try some stuff, see how it goes."
Unknown: That's literally the whole point.
Unknown: Do something different.
Unknown: That's like literally-
Unknown: If it doesn't work
Kenzo: ... that's like literally the whole point.
Unknown: It is.
Kenzo: Like, every conversation I have with Mitch is like, "This is really cool, but how can you tinker with it?"
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah. It's like I mean, its attacks do less damage than your attacks.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, but it has legendary resistance.
Wellby: Do something different.
Kenzo: It does say magical effects. Too worried.
Delwath: Right. It's a lot more durable.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: And
Delwath: it, um...
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Leviathan.
Seeker: Let me get my Leviathan stat block on up here.
Seeker: But then it's like...
Seeker: This is some given page.
Seeker: Where am I looking?
Unknown: Anvil.
Unknown: Oh, you got one more spell too.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Uh, what's a good one?
Delwath: Can be any level? Yeah.
Delwath: Although you're... You might want something that's not 9th level, because your 9th level slot's pretty tapped.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Honestly, Hero's Feast is not a bad choice.
DM: That was always very useful in Risling.
Delwath: No, actually, a good-
Unknown: Very
Delwath: ... a good buffing spell is a good idea.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Or you could just take Force Cage.
DM: Although Force Cage is gonna do literally nothing against a 100-foot long- Yeah ...
Unknown: size ooze.
Unknown: I'll take Hero's Feast.
Delwath: Uh. But is there a better buff spell?
Unknown: No.
Delwath: What does Hero's Feast give you?
DM: Uh, resistance to poison damage, immunity to frightened and poisoned conditions, increases your hit point maximum by 2d10.
DM: But it lasts for 24 hours. It lasts for 24 hours, so it's key 'cause you can cast it before- Right ...
DM: the night before and then rest and get your slot back.
Delwath: All the other good buff spots take concentration, which you can't.
Seeker: I think I added Hero's Feast.
Seeker: What level is that one?
Unknown: Six.
Seeker: Oh, and I can long rest if
Delwath: But what's the point of Hero's Feast?
Seeker: Why wouldn't you just cast it with Wish?
Seeker: So I can save my Wish.
Unknown: Oh, and then rest. Then you rest.
DM: Right. Yeah, that's true. Maybe Hero's Feast isn't that useful.
Delwath: Because the, the point of Hero's Feast is it's 24 hours, so you can cast it the night before.
Delwath: Mm-hmm. But you can do it with Wish the night before.
Unknown: Oh, right, right.
Delwath: There's no upside to knowing it.
Delwath: How m- wait, how many 6th level slots do you have?
Delwath: Two. 'Cause it has to be any spell in the game, right?
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: It's really helpful to have a magic consultant on your team.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: It's helpful to have a DM on your team.
Unknown: [coughs] Well, yeah, exactly.
Unknown: Um.
Wellby: Magic consultant would be a great job title.
Delwath: That would be. [coughs] You want, you want...
Unknown: What does Seeker...
Delwath: Seeker needs a better... I think you need better ways of dealing damage.
DM: Although Chain Lightning- Well, Chain Lightning, that's why we added Chain Lightning.
DM: Yeah. It's a really strong damage dealing spell.
Delwath: It's... Chain Lightning's 6th level?
Unknown: It's 6th level.
Delwath: I mean, there's an argument for something like,
Unknown: um...
DM: What I would, I would pick an 8th level.
DM: I- what about Demiplane? I mean, it's not gonna be useful in the next three hours, but it's this very Seeker-ish spell.
Seeker: What does that one do?
DM: It creates a demiplane that you can-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... like, stash stuff in.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I'm into it. I feel like I've seen reference to that somewhere on my own character sheet.
Seeker: Is it, like, the wand or
Seeker: binding stones?
DM: The binding stones might have a demiplane-ish, 'cause y- you only have one 8th level spell, and Animal Shapes is very, very useful, but not every, not all the time.
Seeker: No, binding stones don't have it.
Seeker: Hmm. All right.
Seeker: That was the Demiplane idea.
DM: I mean, the other potential useful 8th level spell is Mind Blank, which is also a 24-hour buff that gives you immunity to psychic damage and the
Unknown: charmed condition.
Wellby: Didn't you have a ring that does that?
Unknown: Yeah, but
Unknown: I don't know if I'm attuned to it right now.
DM: You're not... I don't think you're attuned to it, 'cause- And also it's not exactly what the ring is.
DM: It just gives you, it gives you advantage against charm.
Delwath: I mean, actually, Demiplane's pretty useful, 'cause we could, you...
Delwath: We could go to a demiplane. It lasts for an hour, so we could short rest in the demiplane and then come back out.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: Yeah. I would probably just take Demiplane. I, I would...
Delwath: Yeah. Demiplane's actually a good ch- It, it, it is actually a really useful, "Hey, we need to, we need, we need 15...
Delwath: We need to go somewhere safe for a half hour to, like-
DM: Okay, so everybody's leveled up.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Goddammit.
DM: Everybody long rest.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: We don't get the ma- the temporary HP things, right?
Kenzo: Why do we sometimes get that? Is that 'cause of something Delweth has done?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Hero feast.
Delwath: Which temporary HP thing?
Kenzo: Like a bunch of sometimes you're like, "You have 28 HP, 28 HP."
Delwath: Oh. Yeah, 'cause I cast Aid.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: But I generally cast Aid every morning.
DM: Right
Delwath: Because Aid asks, lasts for eight hours.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And I can
Delwath: cast it and then make breakfast and short rest again to get my spell slots back.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: So usually-
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: ... you get 20.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So let's, let's begin.
DM: As you wake up
DM: the morning after
DM: you left,
DM: having returned from Limbo and immediately collapsed in exhaustion.
DM: As you awake,
DM: uh, the sun is rising over Orenlas on Vindasharna,
DM: and you're left now
DM: only with the mission to
DM: return to Isengai
DM: and find the ooze that once attempted to destroy your ship,
DM: destroy it, and cleanse the river so the Heartroot can be
DM: replanted.
DM: So
DM: what, what is your...
DM: What do you wanna do? I mean,
DM: you could just teleport straight there.
DM: You could fly the ship.
Seeker: How far are we up?
Delwath: Do we, do we know anything about the-
DM: You don't know anything that's happening in Isengai right now.
DM: You have many
DM: ways to figure that out.
Kenzo: Do some clairvoyance.
Unknown: Send a scry.
Kenzo: Yeah. A scry.
Unknown: Do that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: See what's going on.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo's gonna, um,
Kenzo: uh, go hang out with the Heartroot and
Unknown: tell us-
DM: Well, the Heartroot's still back in...
Delwath: We're in the Elven Forest.
DM: You're in the Elven Forest.
Kenzo: Oh, we have to go back and get the Heartroot.
Unknown: Or we're gonna-
DM: Or send a message to the rangers and say, "Bring the Heartroot."
Unknown: They'll have the... Okay.
Delwath: But we should probably make the space.
Delwath: Like, let's not bring the Heartroot until the ooze is dead, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Like...
DM: That might be risky.
Unknown: Could end badly. Yeah.
Delwath: Could end badly, right?
Unknown: True that.
DM: So-
Seeker: Uh, transplantation we wanna do as quickly as possible, you know.
Unknown: It's like
Seeker: re-potting a plant.
DM: Right.
Seeker: Planting something, you wanna keep it out of the ground.
DM: I mean, Seeker has two 7th level slots now.
DM: You probably wanna teleport to Arbe's and then teleport to Isengai instantaneously with the Heartroot.
Unknown: Cool.
Seeker: Oh, I can take it in itself if it counts as a creature?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: I mean, it's 10 foot by 10... I mean, it's big, but, like, you could, you know,
DM: pick it up.
Unknown: Yeah. That makes sense.
DM: Oh, but also you can teleport objects, can't you?
Unknown: I don't know.
Unknown: That seems like the right idea.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: I think we-
DM: It, it's 600 miles from here, so it's about three days on, on, two and a half days on Vindasharna.
Kenzo: We should bring the ship, yeah?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I think so, right?
Delwath: I think we just, we, we, we set out.
Delwath: I mean, we'll, we'll-
Seeker: A single object
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: We'll set out on Vindasharna towards Isengai.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: Scry.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, so as the, you leave the monks here
DM: to
DM: either return and bring them back to Dunmar, to make their way to Dunmar, they all need a bit of time to recover before they're gonna do anything in the Elven Forest.
DM: It's as good a place as any.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And begin
DM: your trip.
DM: Uh, as you start to sail on Vindasharna, Delweth takes out his silver bowl and begins to scry on,
DM: I guess Isengai.
Delwath: The, yeah, basically to start with where we were.
Delwath: I mean, basically the spot where Vindasharna was attacked last.
DM: Okay.
DM: So, um, you are looking down into a maelstrom of ash.
Unknown: Eh.
DM: You cannot see the city at all beneath you.
DM: It's like a, it's like a hurricane that seems to be growing and spreading out from the city.
DM: It now seems to be stretching about 15 miles in every direction
DM: from your scry.
DM: And the
DM: storm is growing bigger.
DM: [paper rustling]
Unknown: Ow. Huh.
Seeker: Huh. 15 miles in every direction.
Wellby: And it's getting bigger?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: So maybe there's a little urgency.
Seeker: What, is it drawing power from Limbo still or something else?
DM: You can't see it. All that Delweth can see in the scrying mirror is [laughs]
Delwath: You, you know everything I know.
DM: [coughs] A maelstrom of ash swirling below him.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: Um, okay, and it's, like, 600 miles away?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um...
Seeker: Hmm, there was the question of the effect of the
Seeker: explosion we saw inside Limbo-
Unknown: Yep
Unknown: ... on this world.
DM: Um...
Unknown: And maybe it's a backlash.
Unknown: [instrumental music] Let's see.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I, I think the faster
Kenzo: we can get there, the better.
Seeker: Um, but I think- Well, we don't want to teleport into a hurricane.
Kenzo: No, I think we probably don't want to teleport into a hurricane.
Unknown: I think that's true.
Unknown: Um...
Seeker: Well, what kind of approach even is there to fight something that's so big?
Unknown: I...
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Um, Arcana about
Seeker: giant oozes? Was there anything, any precedent for...
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Wait, the oozes is from Limbo, right?
Kenzo: It's a Limbo ooze.
Delwath: We don't know. We don't know at all
Delwath: anything about the ooze.
Wellby: Arcana about oozes, what's our-
Delwath: Literally all we know about the ooze- Yeah ...
Delwath: is we saw it from above, right?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: When we flew over Isengai before, we saw this giant ooze-like thing-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... covering like half the city, and we flew down towards it to investigate, and then it flung a tendril off like-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I remember, yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Like, we know like what color it was and what...
Unknown: That the fact that-
Unknown: Yeah, but
Seeker: ... it was able to use acid to damage the stone ship.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, but, but Michael, it's just...
Kenzo: 'Cause Rai and the monks went to Isengai 'cause that's where the...
Unknown: Right?
DM: That's where the Limbo... Yes, that was where the Limbo
Delwath: woo walked. Wait, but they didn't go to Isengai.
Delwath: Did they go to Isengai?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Oh, okay. They went to Isengai.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, the, the... So I'm saying the ooze is related to Limbo, right?
Kenzo: It's not like the ooze is-
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: The ooze was not there when Rai and the monks went there, and then-
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, it wasn't there when Rai and the monks went there?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Oh, I didn't realize that.
Kenzo: That's the whole thing. It was like a consequence of them like trying to close the vortex or some shit like that.
Unknown: Either the ooze leaks out-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... or it's like, it's like some Limbo ooze or something.
Seeker: So maybe we can use Limbo tricks on it,
Seeker: like try and negate it with our minds.
Unknown: Maybe.
Seeker: From inside Limbo?
Wellby: I don't know if we want to go back to Limbo though.
Seeker: I don't know. No, Limbo's...
Unknown: Let's stay out of Limbo [laughs] right now.
Seeker: But then can we banish it then?
Kenzo: Ah, that's an interesting question.
Kenzo: Does it count as... I feel like that might be a little too easy.
Seeker: Is it a creature?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: It is definitely a creature, yes.
Wellby: Is it... How do we find out if it's native to a different plane?
Kenzo: Uh, did I s- I mean, I must have soul sighted it or like kind of- Ah.
Delwath: Oh ... contact other planes. I'm gonna ask the Tonchi.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Is the ooze a
Delwath: native to Limbo?
Unknown: A creature of Limbo.
Unknown: Sort of. [clears throat]
Kenzo: This is like us fighting the sentient ocean, basically.
Unknown: Hold on. I have five questions.
Seeker: Oh, keep going. Yeah.
Kenzo: It's sort of native to Limbo.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, it um...
Unknown: Is it,
Delwath: is it [coughs] um, does it have goals?
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: interesting.
Unknown: No. Um...
Kenzo: Great question.
Delwath: Does it, uh,
Unknown: um...
Delwath: Does it have...
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: I've got an idea here.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: d- does it,
Unknown: um...
Delwath: I've gotta think of how to ask this. Can, can...
Delwath: This is quite, not quite the right phrasing.
Delwath: Can it be killed by stabbing?
Delwath: But I don't mean exactly that. Like,
Delwath: can we, can we destroy it with the tools and capabilities that we would use against sort of a normal creature?
Seeker: A normal magical creature?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Sort of.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Um, is it growing?
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: Um, one more.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: does it have allies?
Unknown: Ooh.
Unknown: That's a good one.
Seeker: Good question.
Unknown: No. Okay.
Delwath: So it's growing, so I think
Delwath: maybe a leisurely flight to the ooze could backfire.
Kenzo: No, I mean, we should get close, but not...
Delwath: I'm wondering if we could just teleport, but we can't really tele-
DM: can we... Do we have... We don't really have any spells. Remember you also took Wind Walk,
Unknown: Eric.
Unknown: It's 'cause it-
Seeker: That can make us gaseous
DM: ... and you can, you gain a fly speed of 300-
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, that's fast ... feet.
Unknown: So- How long does that last?
Unknown: Eight hours. Oh.
DM: 300 feet
Unknown: per six seconds.
Unknown: That seems useful.
Unknown: Is 35 miles per hour.
DM: No, sorry, it's 600 feet per six seconds 'cause you can dash.
Unknown: 68 miles per hour.
Seeker: So way faster than the ship.
DM: And we have 600 miles to go?
DM: Well, no, 'cause you've been flying for a couple of hours, so you have- Well, we can go 544 miles.
Delwath: So do we have about 500 miles and 50 miles to go?
DM: You have like 580 miles to go.
Delwath: So Wind Walk would get us almost all the way there.
Delwath: ... in a day
Seeker: But do we wanna still have it up when we're encountering the thing?
DM: No, because the only actions you can take in wind form are-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... dash or revert to your normal form.
Wellby: Why would we not just teleport if we need it quick?
Delwath: We... What would we teleport to?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: 'Cause we wanna be, like, not inside of it, but at the edge of it.
Seeker: We wanna approach it.
Wellby: We s- Yeah, we, uh-
Unknown: We have seen it
Wellby: ... we tele- we don't have to teleport...
Wellby: Do we have to teleport to the ground?
Wellby: Can we teleport to the location above Isinge where we last passed over it?
Unknown: That seems too dangerous.
Kenzo: When we got attacked by the tendrils.
Unknown: Yeah, well, yeah.
Unknown: I s-
Delwath: Wait, Seeker just said teleport seems too dangerous?
Seeker: No, being right above it.
Unknown: Are, are you okay, Seeker? [laughs]
Seeker: It's not about the accuracy, which I can guarantee.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: It's about the acid tendrils.
Delwath: But we could be wind walking.
Delwath: We could wind walk.
Seeker: Which really affect my ability to do math
Delwath: ... and then teleport as wind form and then scatter.
DM: No, because the only actions you can take are dash or revert.
Kenzo: Well, I, it feels like we just need to do some reconnaissance, right?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, so why don't we, why don't we get rid of Charner, like, close-ish?
DM: It'll take a long time.
Seeker: Yeah. We'll d- but, well, we'll take it in bursts.
Seeker: We'll go, we'll go a little ways and then-
DM: 'Cause the ooze is growing
Unknown: ... huh?
DM: The ooze is growing.
Unknown: How fast?
Delwath: I didn't think to ask that, but also that's not a yes or no question.
Seeker: So let's get, let's tell Vinder Charner that wind walk gets us within-
Unknown: That's what I'm saying
Unknown: ... eight miles.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That... You're right now.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Oh, let's do it right now then, yeah. If we wind walk now, in eight hours we'd be, like, 10 miles from it.
DM: You'd be 10 miles away.
Seeker: Yeah, let's just do that
DM: ... or 15 miles away.
Unknown: This is the fastest route for us to get there
Unknown: and-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... not teleport right on top of it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Great.
Unknown: Perfect.
Unknown: Let's do it.
Unknown: Done.
DM: So you set Faldric to keep r-
Unknown: That's actually great
DM: ... following along behind as he's gotten used to by now.
DM: Seeker casts wind walk and you fly.
Unknown: Is that seventh level or eighth level, or sixth?
DM: Sixth level.
Delwath: Oh, good. So you can still cast demiplane if we gotta hide.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Oh, there you go.
Seeker: I was looking at the binding stones spells
Seeker: because I think it's... There's a chance we could guess the proper combination of three stones to bind this creature.
Delwath: Ooh. I mean, I like Seeker's chances here.
Unknown: Use-
Unknown: There's a chan- I mean-
Seeker: The, the question is-
Delwath: You mean 100% chance, right, Seeker?
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Uh, we're talking about my intelligence here.
Unknown: Yeah, so.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I have full faith in Seeker's ch- magical chances.
Unknown: But
Seeker: the question is what
Seeker: the spell attack this looks like.
Unknown: Um.
Seeker: The following spells are rumored to be part of the abilities of the stones.
Unknown: Imprisonment stone.
Seeker: Snare Web, Watery Sphere, Magic Circle, Planar Binding, and Imprisonment, which I was just looking at.
Delwath: Imprisonment's pretty good.
Seeker: But it's not permanent. Or is it?
Unknown: Wait.
Delwath: I thought imprisonment was semi-permanent.
Wellby: Wait, could we show the ooze the mirror?
Kenzo: It probably doesn't have a soul. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: That would be pretty amazing though.
Seeker: Oh my God. That's a funny idea.
Seeker: Where are its eyes though? You know?
DM: The downside to imprisonment is there's a save.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Seeker: And this thing, like, probably has legendary resistance to the mirror.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So you can... The, the mirror wouldn't-
Kenzo: I would never work on anything with legendary resistance
Unknown: ... I mean, imprisonment lasts-
Unknown: That's why
Delwath: ... until it's dispelled.
DM: Right.
Delwath: But honestly, it feels a little bit like...
Delwath: That's kind of like-
Seeker: Shortcutting the whole thing
Delwath: ... it's shoving the problem down to somebody else, right?
Delwath: Like, you know-
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: ... when somebody comes along and dispels imprisonment, the ooze will just come back.
Kenzo: Well, this is like what I was saying before.
Kenzo: If we did, like, a, a before, uh, before Talgar our time thing.
Kenzo: Like, we just, we end the campaign by imprisoning some crazy big ooze.
Delwath: We imprisoned the ooze at the end of the last campaign [laughs]
Kenzo: Oh, ex- exactly. Exactly, and then we release it now, you know?
Seeker: We will use minimus containment.
Seeker: The target becomes one inch tall and is trapped inside an indestructible gemstone or similar object.
Delwath: Yeah, but we did that in the previous campaign and it was a little gemstone in limbo that was t- it was trapped and then when Rai tried to pull limbo, the gemstone broke, the spell was
Delwath: dispelled, and then the ooze came out.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: That's how the next campaign ends.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: The next campaign.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Imprisoning the ooze.
DM: Just an endless series of pushing the problem into the future.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] 'Cause it can be dispelled is the point.
Delwath: Imprisonment's not permanent, it's just until it's dispelled.
Seeker: Well, we'll just carry it with us in the, in the, in the portal.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] To the portal.
Seeker: No, it's one inch tall.
DM: No, no. M- the, the minimus containment is, makes it tiny
Delwath: ... it's like, you know, it's like the little-
DM: You trap it in a little gemstone
Delwath: ... little demon, demon trapped in a gemstone.
Wellby: Would be crazy enough.
Delwath: The real problem is it's guaranteed to fail because the ooze is guaranteed to have at least one legendary resistance.
DM: You'd have to burn all of its legendary resistance first.
Unknown: We'd have to burn, we'd have to burn all of it.
Seeker: Yeah. We, we need a variety of tactics here in our pocket.
Unknown: Now-
Seeker: This is one option.
Delwath: The a- Wait, the answer was can we kill it was sort of?
DM: Can you,
DM: can you kill it? It was
DM: y- yeah. Well, it was mostly.
Unknown: Right. Okay.
Delwath: So I mean, it is an idea to, to be like, wow, if we, if we wear it down and it's, it's like vulnerable to a spell, then
Delwath: that's a possibility.
Seeker: I'd say I'll keep the binding stones in my pocket 'cause they're always in my pocket.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, nothing could possibly go wrong using them for the very first time in a high stakes combat situation, right?
Seeker: That's what they've been there for, waiting eternal.
Kenzo: You need to use the binding... How do you not use the binding stones yet?
Kenzo: You gotta use those.
Seeker: It's, I've looked at them as an option many times.
Unknown: It's like, huh.
Delwath: Th- it's not super clear how they work.
Delwath: Like, do you have specific th- You don't actually know what they can do, right?
Seeker: None of the abilities are combat things 'cause, like-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... imprisonment is one minute, so.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: That's really the issue.
Unknown: Right
DM: Okay, so we are...
DM: So you now, you fly as
DM: gaseous clouds,
DM: 70 miles an hour racing across the landscape of, landscape of the Plaguelands, following the river from,
DM: that just goes down from the Orenlas Forest to join the Istaros right near Isengai.
DM: Um, you pass over a
DM: huge extance- expanse of,
DM: uh,
DM: completely
DM: burned forest with the trees still standing, but blackened and burned.
Unknown: That's weird.
DM: Um, you pass over a open,
DM: um,
DM: uh-
Delwath: Wait, that's just south of Orenlas?
DM: That's, uh, halfway between Orenlas and
DM: Isengai, roughly.
Delwath: Do you know what's that just out of game-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... do you know what's there? Okay. Wait, I might talk to you about that separately.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, you pass over
DM: a,
DM: um, large expanse of rolling hills, um, and piles of ash and slag that swirl and blow in the wind.
Wellby: You don't think we did this, right?
Wellby: You know, this is not related to what happened in Limbo.
Seeker: Almost certainly there are side effects here of the-
DM: No, this predates what happened in Limbo.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: This is the Plaguelands.
Wellby: Oh.
Delwath: I mean, we did it by not stopping Chelavate from creating the Great Plague, but-
Wellby: But this is not related to the, like the ash explosion.
Unknown: No.
DM: No.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: So.
Wellby: Yeah. Okay.
DM: And then you, um, cross
DM: a slow meandering ash clogged river,
DM: and follow it until you can see the edge of this...
DM: In fact, where wis- where Windwalk ends is basically at the edge of this growing ash storm, which is about 15 miles away from the, from Isengai.
Unknown: Oh my God.
DM: And you're standing on a hill,
DM: a low hill. Actually, as you settle out of wind form, your feet sink about six inches into ash,
DM: and
DM: you're walking across. It's like a lunar landscape.
DM: Everything is just coated in dust and ash.
DM: And you're looking-
Delwath: Death plague because of what we did in Limbo
DM: ... you're looking across-
Kenzo: Ash is a triggering word.
DM: Yeah. [laughs] You're looking across this growing storm that looks like
DM: a, almost like a hurricane with winds blowing up to make, that's picking up the ash on the ground and making a, a
DM: obscured wall
DM: beyond which you can't see.
Seeker: So we don't even know if there's news here at all.
DM: I mean,
DM: that's true.
Seeker: We shouldn't make too many assumptions.
Seeker: Well, how do we find out what's going on here?
Seeker: I could clairvoyance inside it.
DM: Um.
Unknown: But we'll just see ash.
Unknown: How far away is it?
DM: Isengai is about 15 miles from here.
DM: You're at the edge of the ash storm, and it's creeping towards you.
Kenzo: Wellby, should you send some animals into this?
Wellby: Uh, I mean, they, they'll die.
Wellby: We already know what the result will be.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, I have an i- uh, hold on.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: How can we recon without-
Delwath: I have an idea. Can we get a little closer?
Unknown: Let's go a little closer.
DM: I mean, you can walk.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Walking.
DM: But you're gonna walk into the storm if you go more than about two miles.
Delwath: Okay. Let's go to the edge of the storm.
Delwath: Right. So like, let's, I wanna stop like 500 feet from the edge of the storm.
DM: Okay. Well, it's not, it's, as you get closer, it's not, it's not like a sharp edge.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's like there's winds blowing, and you can see maybe 200 yards into the storm as you get closer.
DM: Just from a distance, it looks
DM: like, it looks like the edge of a thunderstorm or something, right?
DM: So there's like, you can see an edge, but there's winds blowing and it's picking up the ash.
DM: Um, the winds just get more intense as you go in, and so the ash on the ground is being lifted and tossed.
Delwath: Um, hold on one second.
Seeker: Uh, there's 10 rounds in a minute.
Delwath: Wow, this is actually, this can go a long way.
Unknown: Wait, is that right?
Delwath: So if something can move,
Unknown: if something can move
Delwath: 120 feet and it can m- take two moves in a turn, right, that, if it's running, something that, that can move 120, it could go 240 feet every six seconds, right?
DM: Yep.
Delwath: Okay, so 240 feet every six seconds is like half a mile every minute,
Delwath: right? So in an hour...
DM: Well, you can't, unless you're in wind form, I mean, you can't dash every round for an hour.
Delwath: What if you're an intangible creature?
DM: Possibly then you could, yes.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: oh, no. It can only move...
Seeker: Yeah, you can up to twice...
Delwath: Oh, no, no, no, no. It can't.
Delwath: Never mind, I, it's only half that speed.
Delwath: That's okay. It only needs to be half that speed.
Delwath: Um, 14 miles.
Unknown: So
Delwath: 14 miles, I mean, the heart of Isengai is, the, the distance from here to the ooze is probably only
Delwath: 10 miles, right, we think?
DM: Somewhere between 10 and 15 miles.
Delwath: Okay. So when we get close, Delwath will disappear, and an identical copy of Delwath appears right next to Delwath.
Unknown: Delwath.
Delwath: And Delwath says, "It's okay, don't, I'm still here, invisible,"
Delwath: and sends his copy running into the, this is mislead.
Wellby: Delwath two.
Delwath: Yeah, Delwath two. The first new...
Delwath: Yes. So-
Unknown: What?
Unknown: Th-
Seeker: Well, strictly speaking, three, because there was a thing like her Delwath.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: So it's an illusory double, right?
Delwath: The double lasts for the duration.
Delwath: You can move the double up to twice your speed- You can see through its eyes and hear through its air, ears as if you were looking where it was.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: That's awesome. That's perfect. So- Wow
Seeker: ... it can- Run right into the ash. Yeah ...
Delwath: it just runs right into the ash. It's, it's a,
Delwath: it's intangible and invulnerable.
Unknown: That's amazing.
DM: Perfect.
Unknown: So perfect.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: So since my speed is, is 60, it can move 120 each turn that I can take attack, magic action, so.
Unknown: Double prime. Um-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... so it's 120 feet, so every minute it moves 200, it moves 1200 feet.
DM: It's s- it's 120 feet per round, right?
Delwath: Yeah. So it can move 14 miles in an hour.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And the spell lasts for an hour, which is why the hour matters.
Delwath: But I'm just gonna send it...
Delwath: But it uses my senses, so it has true sight, it has dark vision.
DM: [sighs]
Delwath: I mean, I can see through it with my senses as if I-
DM: As if you were looking
Seeker: ... as if I'm in its position. What do you see?
DM: Uh, oh, wait, hold on.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Didn't think we'd just run right through the ash, did you, Tim?
DM: Uh, no, I was just calculating, um,
DM: when it's gonna get to where it, where you see.
DM: So you run,
DM: um,
DM: through
DM: a growing storm of wind.
DM: Um, the first couple of miles, uh, is maybe lightly obscured as you're crossing across these sort of rolling hills that were once pleasant agricultural
DM: valleys. Um, there is no structures remaining here whatsoever.
DM: Any villages or towns or anything have long since been destroyed.
DM: Over the course of the next six miles or so, so eight miles total, you,
DM: ash gets denser and denser until, um, about, I don't know, two thirds of the way into the spell.
DM: It's, the visibility is something like only about 30 feet in front of you.
DM: You can see hardly anything.
DM: Um,
DM: true sight is irrelevant here 'cause you're, it's ash.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You keep running.
DM: Uh, slightly further, you, uh, after about 50 minutes, um, or no, it's a little bit before that, um, 45 minutes, you start to
DM: pass through the...
DM: Uh, I mean, no, maybe about 50 minutes, the outskirts of what might have been Isengai.
DM: You can see just every now and then, like mostly it's completely destroyed, but every now and then you'll see a,
DM: you know, a part of a wall standing or like a little stretch of, um, buildings that kind of make a little bit of a, of a bit of a road,
DM: pillars standing like that.
DM: Um,
DM: at,
DM: uh,
DM: 59 minutes and, uh-
Unknown: Oh, it lasts an hour
DM: ... it lasts an hour, and-
Delwath: Oh, you know what? Hold on.
Delwath: It lasts two hours.
Delwath: I'm gonna metamagic it.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: It's why, why it's better to double the duration.
DM: Uh-
Delwath: It's more useful.
DM: Okay. Well, at 59 minutes and 24 seconds, um,
DM: it comes to a,
DM: like the eye of a hurricane style, like very intense wind tunnel.
Delwath: No, hold on. I might not be able to do it. Hold on.
Delwath: I can't rem- Hold on. Keep talking.
Delwath: A, a- an eye, okay. Yeah.
DM: And you stumble through into a clear open space.
Unknown: Ooh.
DM: Um, about 600 feet across, um, still lightly obscured as m- mist and ash sort of drift in through the center
DM: of this storm. Um,
DM: there is,
DM: uh,
DM: there's a, there's a dome overhead, so it's like there's a, the clouds, the ash clouds are sort of sitting on top, so you can't see the sky from here.
DM: Got it. I can only double range, not duration.
DM: Okay. Well, you have, uh-
Unknown: 30 seconds
DM: ... 36 seconds
DM: of it inside the clear spot.
DM: Um, three things that you quickly notice from inside the clear spot.
DM: Uh,
DM: first, um,
DM: you can see this is, this is, at the very edge of the clear spot, um, maybe just be- like just beyond the wall, like you can see it sloping down towards the river.
DM: You can't actually see the river.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: It's on the other side of the, of the ash.
DM: Um, but you can see the docks, like where the, the river port would've started.
DM: There's a, a few little buildings that suggest.
DM: Um, there is a, um, in the center here, there's what might have used to been a plaza or something, or a city well or something like that,
DM: and you can see like a, a big well like this that's cracked and split.
DM: And stretching out from the well, you see a one like long pseudopod of some kind of ooze-like creature.
Delwath: So it's stretching from the well into the ash?
DM: No, no, into the clear spot.
DM: It's like-
Seeker: Mostly it's in the well
DM: ... mostly it's in the well.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: And there's like one pseudopod that comes out of the well and is just like-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... um-
Unknown: Feeling around
DM: ... feeling around.
Seeker: I wonder if it went there to hide from the ash storm.
Unknown: Maybe.
Kenzo: Yeah. Does this, does it look like it's hiding?
Kenzo: Does, does it look like it doesn't like the ash?
Seeker: Does it react to somebody walking up to it?
DM: Um-
Delwath: I mean, it looks like Delwath. You don't know it's a delusion, but-
DM: Uh, yes. Uh, three more pseudopods shoot out of the well and start, something-
Delwath: I mean, Delwath
DM: ... start pulling and crawling, and you start to see like this bubbling mass start to ooze up out of the well-
Unknown: But I'm sure Delwath would love a sword
DM: ... and start to rush towards you.
Unknown: And charge it.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: What does it do?
DM: Uh, it's, um [paper crumpling]
Unknown: Wait, let me see.
Unknown: Hm?
DM: It is going to-
Unknown: Let me see
DM: ... three, three pseudopods come flying [whooshing] all three straight towards Delweth once, when you hit about 60 feet away from it.
DM: Like three of these acidic pods, pseudopods just like shoot out across the plaza to strike at you.
DM: But nothing happens because you're invulnerable and illusory.
DM: And now you have about six seconds left.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: So wait, what about Kong's question?
Unknown: Is it-
DM: Sorry, what was your question?
Seeker: Is it harmed by the ash?
Unknown: The ooze.
DM: It doesn't,
DM: it doesn't seem to care about the ash particularly.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Huh. Like it doesn't stay inside the eye?
DM: Well, the, the area's like 600 feet across.
Unknown: 600, 600.
DM: It's in the middle.
DM: What it looks like is that it like lives in the sewers.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: [coughs] And it is now crawl...
DM: It's like was looking at, poked out of this well and is looking around.
DM: Maybe it's simultaneously looking out of every well in the city.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: Ah, collective consciousness ooze.
DM: [clears throat]
Delwath: Well, double Delweth will charge and disappear.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And then I'll cast Scrying and that's fine.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh, very good. 'Cause now I've seen it.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: So now we can, it, we have in a more leisurely fashion take 10 minutes to look around and see what we see.
DM: So the, you see now spreading out-
Unknown: And then end the teleport there
DM: ... about 100-
Unknown: [laughs] That's exactly
Unknown: what it was, yeah
DM: ... 100 feet.
Unknown: But-
DM: Stretching about 100 feet wide, you can see now this like bubbling mass that seems to be searching around the edges of the plaza with these pseudopods, like trying
DM: to figure out what happened to this creature that vanished.
Unknown: The ooze is not very smart.
Delwath: Is it like filling up the whole-
DM: No, it's like 100 f-...
DM: The, the center of the mass is like maybe only 80 or 100 feet across, but it ha-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... but these pseudopods extend.
Delwath: Are there any like buildings or places to hide in this clearing?
DM: Um, there's,
DM: uh, all that sur- Like most of this has been,
DM: it seems actually possibly, um, s- partially consumed by the ooze because as it's bubbling out, you see like little bits of stone and stuff like floating and decaying in this body.
DM: But there is what might have once been a,
DM: a, like a, a covered market or something.
DM: There's a row of columns that are each about 10 feet tall, and then the roof has cracked and fallen down, and there's like a line, a diagonal line that goes about 40 feet long
DM: of piled rubble.
Delwath: And did you say before this, the river runs right past this, like the bank of the river?
DM: The river is like, so I'll just...
DM: It's not, this is not a to scale sketch, but the basic-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... to the well, there's like a big plaza like this.
DM: Somewhere like here is the river, but you can't see it 'cause the ash goes like that.
DM: But you can see like docks and infrastructure that suggests the river is that way.
Delwath: Okay, so this was probably a riverside plaza.
DM: Yeah, and then there's a, what once was a market here where all that remains is the front row of columns.
Unknown: Excellent.
DM: But there's a roof that fell and, um, f- forms a line of rubble.
Delwath: I'm just trying to think about why this would be- So- ...
Delwath: an eye of a storm.
Seeker: I was wondering the same thing. Why is it here?
Kenzo: Okay, so one, one thing.
Kenzo: Do we have ways, 'cause like it feels like- Water back ...
Kenzo: it feels like we're gonna have to end up in the sewer.
Kenzo: Like, like wherever the ooze, the ooze is like down.
Kenzo: Yeah. It's down there someplace, so.
Delwath: Or we draw it out. Yeah.
Kenzo: Draw it out. Or we draw it out, but I'll, I'll...
Kenzo: Like again, it, it feels like however we're gonna defeat this thing, it's not gonna be like, like chopping off some pseudopod tendrils.
Kenzo: Right. You know what I mean? There must be like some core or something- There's like a- ...
Kenzo: or brain or something ... exactly, exactly, exactly. There's, there's gotta be s- And that's likely deep underground.
Seeker: The ooze nugget. What's that? The ooze nugget.
Kenzo: Yeah, whatever. The ooze, yeah.
Kenzo: The ooze, the ooze central nervous system brain thing.
Kenzo: It's like a super giant thing. Is there a way for us to like explore in the sewers, like without going there?
Kenzo: Like can we like, uh, you know, drone map it or something?
Unknown: Like how do we, uh-
Seeker: Oh, 'cause your thing that you can send out can't go very far, but we can send a bat to Del- The thing I can send out can go super far.
Seeker: It's just- Oh, the one you just did. Yeah. Can you do that again?
Delwath: Yeah, but we have to be...
Delwath: The problem is we're 50 miles from- But we're at the r- we're at range.
Delwath: We're 50 miles from here. Yeah.
Delwath: So I can create an illusory double of myself that lasts for an hour.
Delwath: Huh. But, and it can move twice my speed,
Delwath: but otherwise it's the same as Delweth.
Delwath: So like it doesn't have-
Kenzo: We can't like cast spells and fight and stuff.
Kenzo: No. Yeah. No, but for, for, this is perfect.
Kenzo: For, for the reconnaissance it's perfect.
Kenzo: We, but we wanna go... Yeah, like right?
Delwath: Like is there a good way to map the sewer?
Delwath: I mean- Or go check out the sewer without going in there ...
Seeker: can we animal shape to, you fly out above the eye of the storm, briefly turn into Delweth while falling, cast your double,
Seeker: and then you can- And die ... animal shape and then fly back.
Delwath: No, you have to re-animal shape me.
Seeker: I can't from this distance.
Seeker: Exactly. Can you switch... I think you can go back and forth, right?
Delwath: Can you switch yourself with animal shape?
Seeker: I think so. Okay.
Kenzo: Tim, is the sewer, is the ooze just like clogging up a sewer entirely or is it, or the, like the well- Why don't you, why don't you...
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Yeah, uh, Tim, fucking, uh, commune with nature.
Kenzo: What the hell's going on? Yeah, yeah.
DM: Ah.
Unknown: Oh, oh my God. Oh my God.
DM: So many things are going on.
Kenzo: Yeah. Can you... So, oh my God, what the fuck do I do?
Kenzo: [laughs] Commune with nature and then also, yeah, dude, like, like the ooze like, like 'cause it's, it's an, it's an entity, right?
Kenzo: It's got consciousness. Like- Can't you get like a radar map?
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. Yeah, well also to...
Kenzo: And, and if it is, like it, this is actually really interesting.
Kenzo: Is the consciousness like uniformly, um, exhibited throughout the physical system of the ooze?
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Mm.
Kenzo: Or is it centralized into like a, you know, like the core, the brain of the consciousness is like, you know, deep down.
Kenzo: Anyways, what's going on?
DM: Ah, okay.
Unknown: Commune with nature first.
DM: Yes. Um, actually for this I'm gonna say make a insight check.
DM: Um, it has to be Seeker that turns the targets back in as the spell caster takes a [paper rustles]
Seeker: That's right. I was just looking it up and found that out too.
Kenzo: What's my, is my insight like plus a billion now?
Unknown: [die thuds]
DM: Your insight is gonna be like, it's gonna be plus high now 'cause you've got better wisdom.
DM: Plus 12 or 13 or something like that.
DM: [die thuds]
Seeker: Yeah. [paper rustles] Plus 12, that's nice.
Unknown: [paper rustles] [upbeat music]
DM: It's sick.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Wow. Oh my God.
Kenzo: Oh, this is so cool. All my things are so much more awesome now.
Kenzo: This is great. All right. [paper rustles] Plus 12.
Unknown: [paper rustles]
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Wait.
DM: So Kenzo goes into his trance and reaches out your consciousness for, you can now stretch something like 40 miles or something like that.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Wow. [upbeat music] I could do 39 before, so it's gotta be more than that.
DM: Oh, yeah. It's-
Unknown: Whatever
DM: ... yeah, yeah. Whatever. It doesn't matter.
DM: It's plenty long enough to, to get a sense of this place.
DM: Um,
DM: there are...
DM: The first, the first thing you notice is that there is,
DM: um,
DM: there is not a single, there's not like one...
DM: You don't sense any like single consciousness.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: In fact, it's hard to describe this as a consciousness at all.
DM: What you sense is a,
DM: a
DM: like just a disordering of...
DM: It's actually like, it reminds you of the Heartroot, but completely inverted by chaos.
Kenzo: Ooh, Chaosroot.
DM: And it's stre- like you can see actually the n- you actually suspect that what you're seeing in your mind as you stretch through is like a map of the sewers-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... and tunnels underneath the city where you see like lines of this.
DM: It's almost like the filamentous like-
Unknown: Yeah, mycelial
DM: ... mycelial of-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... the Heartroot, but all like Limbo ooze network instead.
DM: [paper rustles]
Delwath: So it's the anti Heartroot.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: But it is concentrated most strongly in,
DM: uh, it is densest, the like structure is densest in three places.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Three places.
DM: Um,
DM: one is in the river.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: The second is, um,
DM: what you guess is this pl- like it, what it feels like is...
DM: So you're doing this while Delwath is scrying and you're sort of layering on your like radar consciousness map of what Delwath is seeing, and it feels like it's dr- like
DM: it's condensing.
DM: So around the s- the center of this plaza, the consciousness is very thin and it's all like pulled together into a, it's almost like it extract, it pulled bits of itself
DM: from all the sewers around here to emerge out and search for Delwath.
DM: Right? So it's like the density is higher here.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: It's condensed here.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: That's just nice. Wait, there's a third.
DM: The third is at this, there is something else at this location that doesn't feel like a consciousness.
DM: It feels like,
DM: um,
DM: so...
Wellby: Hang on. Something else like not the ooze whatsoever at all?
DM: Maybe it's related to the ooze.
DM: It's hard to say.
DM: It's...
DM: So when you were, when you were attempt- when you were like vibing with the tree in-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... Limbo, right, and you got your little chaos key,
DM: uh,
DM: there's a,
DM: there's like a flavor of the plane that you sensed and there's like a scar, like a nodule or some kind of,
DM: um,
DM: something like that that has the same taste in your mind.
DM: Some like little bit of Limbo at the bottom of this well.
Kenzo: The bottom of this well. So the bottom of the well, the riverbank, and where's the third place again?
DM: The plaza.
Kenzo: The plaza in general. Okay.
Kenzo: [paper rustles] Okay. All right. Communicate that to all the friends.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: so, but j- just to, you know, 'cause c- communication, like, uh, is what's the, what's the deal with like other, other kind of like life forms?
DM: So there's v- there's nothing else alive in this.
DM: There's nothing that's not part, somehow part of the ooze that's alive in this, okay?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: The storm is clearly unnatural.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: And you can sense that it's growing as well.
Unknown: The storm is unnatural.
DM: And it is centered on this like little nodule of Limbo.
Delwath: Oh. Which, the one in...?
DM: At the bottom of the well.
Unknown: Right. Okay. [paper rustles]
Kenzo: The bottom of the well, plaza, and river.
Wellby: Those are the three-
Unknown: Wait
Wellby: ... those are the three-
Delwath: The bottom of the well and the plaza are two different...
Unknown: They're the same.
DM: Well, they're just...
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Wellby: Bottom of the well, like but-
DM: Plaza top, bottom of the well bottom.
Delwath: Okay. But like the, the-
DM: That well, yes, yes, yes
Delwath: ... the eye of the storm is where two of the nodules are effectively.
DM: Well, the, the concentration of ooze matter is on top of the plaza, and then the nodule of Limbo is at the bottom of the well.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Unknown: [die thuds]
DM: And then the river is also the, another high concentration of ooze matter.
DM: [die thuds]
Unknown: Uh, well last,
Unknown: we have to come-
Kenzo: I feel like we have to fight our way, better fight our way down there.
DM: Not first and just-
Kenzo: Just c- just, just do it
Wellby: ... get it over with?
Kenzo: I mean, I mean we could teleport and just see what happens.
Wellby: Like brain, right?
DM: Uh. [laughs]
Kenzo: I know approximately where the nodule is.
Wellby: We could st- are there any of them where there's an easier exit than the other that we could go in and sort of do our exploratory expedition first?
Seeker: Right. Map a route through the sewers for us.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Not from the plaza coming from somewhere else.
Delwath: I mean, when did the, when did my double start getting into the...
Delwath: Like how big is the city? Like how far is it from here to the edge of the city?
DM: Uh, that was about... The city, Isingue is never, was never a big city, right?
DM: So it's, I don't know, a-
Unknown: A mile?
DM: Yeah, something like that, right? It's like not a large...
DM: And this, this is, this, the docks are close to the center of the city.
Delwath: Right. So maybe not even. Maybe it's a mile, maybe like half a mile.
DM: Less than a mile. So it's probably half a mile from the edge of the city.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: And the sewers don't extend...
DM: Right, like the storm, Kenzo, which says the s- the storm extends way beyond the edge of the city itself.
Unknown: Right. Right.
DM: And the ooze, the ooze is just concentrated in the city, in the sewers of the city.
Delwath: But the, the ooze didn't seem to react to my...
Delwath: I mean, there was no reaction to my...
Delwath: Do we have any reason to think we would be in danger sneaking into the ash?
Delwath: I mean, other than the fact that the ash might have all kinds of bad...
Delwath: I just, if we get closer, we have a lot more options.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Did we learn anything from defeating the crazy ash centipede
Unknown: goblin army thing?
Unknown: Like a castle.
Unknown: Like when we were over there?
Unknown: Yeah. 'Cause
Seeker: like didn't we end up using radiant damage against it?
Delwath: No, it was resistant to radiant damage.
DM: It was resistant to radiant.
Delwath: Can you soul sight the ooze from here?
Unknown: Well, I was gonna say, yeah.
Delwath: No, probably not.
Kenzo: Not, not from here, but, um, but Tim, I-
DM: From an edge of, from the edge of the sewer you could.
Kenzo: Tim, Kenzo will, uh, um, kind of engage the ooze consciousness.
Kenzo: Like I'm gonna, um...
Seeker: Just let it know we're here.
Kenzo: Well, um, so basically what I'm kind of curious about is like i- i- 'cause you kind of asked it does it have goals?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right? And it doesn't.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: It did not. Right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But it might want to go home.
Kenzo: Yeah. So that, that's what... It's like, it's like does it, is it, is it just, um...
Kenzo: Yeah, I kind of reach out to the ooze consciousness and...
Kenzo: This is sort of like when animals try to like kind of...
Kenzo: Like I, I get close so that like the ooze consciousness maybe-
Unknown: It can sniff your hand. Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. It's kind of like aware that there's like something else there.
Delwath: Do we know, do we know it is... No.
Delwath: Oh, sorry. Finish.
Kenzo: So i- is there like a sensation that the ooze is just like,
Kenzo: is just like kind of reacting and like lashing out and just like...
Unknown: Or, or is it like...
Kenzo: Yeah. Is there something there? Is it soothable?
Unknown: Is it like-
DM: So you don't have any sense that it has a...
Unknown: Agency or-
DM: Yeah, it's not, um...
DM: It's not, it doesn't react to your mind as if ev- as if it has like conscious will.
Delwath: So like a Limbo slime mold?
DM: It's basically... Yeah, it's Limbo slime mold.
Unknown: Okay. Okay, got it. Got it.
Unknown: It's basically a slime mold. Yeah.
Kenzo: And then the three, the three nodules, like you know, like there's like kind of more density.
Kenzo: Like is there a sense that at the more dense nodules, like maybe the consciousness is a little different?
Kenzo: Like is it more intelligent at the nodules, or is it just the whole thing is kind of...
DM: No, it's not...
DM: It just seems... It al- I mean, it's almost seemed like it was...
DM: Like a slime mold is, is really the best way to think about it, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
DM: It's
DM: not, um...
DM: It doesn't have the, it doesn't have anything like the sort of sentience and, and sort of will that the Heartroot does, right?
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's like... But it is like the anti-Heartroot in that it's like a network of these-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... slime tendrils, but it seems to operate like entirely on instinct.
DM: And instinct is just make everything Limbo.
Unknown: Got it.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: The ques- the answer to did it have allies was sort of?
DM: No, the answer to allies was no.
Delwath: Oh, no. Okay.
DM: But that's just because it's all part of the same thing.
Kenzo: Well, this i- this is like cancer. You just need to like chemotherapy it and just like-
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: How do we, how do we like nuke the whole thing?
Unknown: Water.
Delwath: Magic damage.
Unknown: Fire.
Kenzo: Let's go try to destroy one of the nodules and see what, how it goes.
Unknown: We'll learn a lot.
Unknown: Yeah. We'll start with the-
Kenzo: We'll learn a lot by trying to like-
Unknown: Exactly
Kenzo: ... you know.
Seeker: I, I'm wondering if we can send it back to Limbo somehow.
Unknown: But is it...
Delwath: The answer of was it from Limbo was sort of.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Cool if we could like talk to it or something, but.
Kenzo: Can we show it to the mirror?
Unknown: [laughs] That's interesting.
Unknown: The ooze.
Unknown: In principle, yes.
Delwath: I mean, possibly we could go...
Delwath: We could do a reconnaissance mission to get a piece of it,
Unknown: right?
Seeker: Oh, that's a fun idea.
Delwath: And then like retreat.
Kenzo: I kind of like that. I want to learn about this thing 'cause I thought it was like, you know, it's like a little like...
Seeker: How... Okay. How are we gonna get some?
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: Well, we want to go to the edge of the city and like enter a sewer or something like that where-
Kenzo: Well, it's, it's super reactive.
Kenzo: It'll come. It'll, it's gonna-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... it's gonna come try to attack us.
Wellby: Yeah. Let's just pick one place and go for it.
Seeker: What is the hazard of walking through the ash?
Unknown: Let's find out.
Unknown: Uh.
Kenzo: Can we send something to the...
Unknown: [laughs] Kenzo.
Seeker: Someone goes first into the ash to find out what it's like.
Kenzo: I mean, I'm an astral projection.
DM: You can do astral.
Kenzo: Yeah. I'll, I'll... Okay, that's fine. Yeah. I'll, I'll, I'll, uh, I'll be an astral, uh...
DM: Just astral project and go as a...
DM: Yeah, okay.
Kenzo: I'll just step into it and see what happens.
DM: Um.
Seeker: Oh, oh, oh, we forgot to do Seeker Seven overnight.
Seeker: I mean, we were very tired.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Seeker: Did we do that? Should we have done that?
Delwath: Wait, and weren't we talking about doing Hero's Feast?
Seeker: We also forgot to do that.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: But we could...
Delwath: Uh, it's the end of... I mean, I think it's reasonable.
Delwath: I... Here's, here's my suggestion on the plan.
Delwath: We do a reconnaissance. We get a piece of it, right?
Unknown: We can take our time with it.
Delwath: We study it, right?
Delwath: We... There's a few things we can do with the piece of it, right?
Delwath: Like in theory, reconnaissance, Kenzo can s- soul sight it.
Delwath: We can-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: And then long-
Unknown: Show the mirror. Show your mirror
Delwath: ... and then we'll long rest.
Unknown: Okay. Let's, let's do a long rest.
Delwath: Right? Before we actually enter, we'll like retreat to somewhere a little bit safe.
Delwath: We'll camp.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: We'll do a long rest so we can pick one, either Hero's Feast or Seeker Seven.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Great. Good idea.
Seeker: Thank you, Tim. Thank you.
Unknown: We do all that.
DM: Okay. So who's... Wait, who's going into the ash first?
Unknown: So-
DM: Ken's our astral projection.
DM: Make-
Kenzo: I, well, it's, I'm like, I'm like, I astral...
Kenzo: And then, and then like I stick my pinky in.
DM: Well, nothing happens when you stick your-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Nothing happens when you stick your pinky in.
Unknown: There's not like a clear edge.
DM: And it's not a sharp boundary, right?
DM: It just, on the edge it-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... it just gets increasingly...
DM: [machine beeping] What was that?
Unknown: Dishwasher?
DM: Is the fridge open or is the coffee, or is that the coffee pot?
Unknown: No, that was the coffee pot turning off.
Delwath: Coffee pot turning off.
DM: Okay
Wellby: The coffee pot's gone.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. Kenzo will just walk.
Unknown: He'll just...
Unknown: Make a constitution saving throw.
Unknown: Damn it.
Seeker: So there is some hazard of the ash.
Kenzo: When, when, when did, when did, when did I have to make it?
Kenzo: Like, what ha- at what point did I get to something that triggers a constitution-
DM: Um, you go in maybe...
DM: Uh, it's... Actually, sorry, actually, don't make a constitution saving throw 'cause the first bit of the...
DM: For a while, the ash is fairly thin, right?
Unknown: So it's just-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... like you can see it's, it's like lightly obscured.
DM: You can still see a few hundred feet.
DM: You can feel the sort of ash blowing against you.
DM: The winds are sort of very variable, like blowing in all sorts of directions and, um...
Unknown: But it's like, I mean, like you're...
Unknown: It's hard to breathe.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And as you go deeper, as it gets more and more obscured...
Kenzo: So how far have I walked now?
Unknown: Like maybe a mile.
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Okay.
Kenzo: So I, I'm c- I can still tell that and communicate with the team.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I'm giving them a, a full update.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: So about a mile in, make a constitution saving throw.
Unknown: Yeah. [die rolling] Uh-oh.
Unknown: 12.
Unknown: You are poisoned.
Kenzo: Bardic. No, I'm not. I'm immune to poison.
Unknown: Oh, you are not poisoned.
Kenzo: [laughs] I tell everybody, "I would've been poisoned if I, if I could be."
Unknown: You're just choking on the ash, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's like toxic.
Kenzo: Yeah, it sucks. Okay.
Unknown: I come back.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: What did we learn?
Kenzo: Uh, it's poisonous ash. Like you guys will probably choke on it.
Kenzo: I'm immune to poison, but you guys will probably, uh...
Kenzo: So you know, the, the, the, uh, the eye of the storm place where there's no ash, that's a good place to be.
Wellby: Maybe let's go there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: right. But then the ooze will attack us.
Kenzo: So but if our goal is just to do like a little reconnaissance, then we could just like teleport there,
Kenzo: grab a little ooze.
Delwath: Let it attack us, like cut off a piece of it and flee?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Do we all need to go?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Well, we do. He has teleport.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs] Do we all need to go?
Seeker: 'Cause I have like some other shit to do, so...
Unknown: Oh, no.
Wellby: Doctor's appointment. [laughs] Oh my God, is it Tuesday?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Um, I mean...
Delwath: The other option is to-
Wellby: Do people.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: The, there's another option here which is to, to, to, um...
Delwath: I was gonna take a nap today.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: How about
Unknown: nah.
DM: Seeker's really ready to settle down.
Unknown: Yeah, this is like-
DM: This adventuring thing is getting him.
Kenzo: It's like this reluctant golden dragon.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Like this is like... [laughs]
Seeker: I've just had my, my cloak dry cleaned again.
Unknown: [laughs] I know.
Wellby: You just had a vision of like the entire multiverse.
Wellby: Like you just had the most intense trip of your life.
Unknown: That's so true.
Unknown: Right, right.
Kenzo: That's so true. You just saw the whole multiverse.
Wellby: None of this is real, man.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Um... [laughs]
Delwath: Is the poison is the problem?
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: It's all self-transforming machine elves.
Unknown: So-
Delwath: Uh, green dragons are immune to poison.
Unknown: Interesting.
Wellby: How many of us could be green dragons here?
DM: Well, here at Ceas makes you immune to poison.
Unknown: Ah. Ah.
Wellby: Maybe we could cure-
Delwath: Well, so...
Unknown: Okay. That's something.
Delwath: So but here's...
Unknown: So
Delwath: we could um,
Delwath: we could do a
Delwath: Kenzo and Delweth...
Delwath: I could turn into a green dragon.
Delwath: Kenzo could ride my back. We could fly in, get a piece of the ooze, and get out.
Kenzo: That's cool. I can still soul sight it.
Seeker: And Wellby and I do really important work back here in the meantime.
Delwath: Like your dentist appointment.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That sounds like a plan.
Wellby: And some laundry.
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, that's an immune to poison strategy that works pretty well.
Kenzo: That's true. Yeah, we're both immune to poison.
Kenzo: We roll up, fly through the ash,
Kenzo: go and... Look, I just want to soul sight it.
Unknown: Soul sighting it would be very useful.
Delwath: Yeah, and I think if we can like swoop down and like take a piece of it
Unknown: somehow.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We wanna like bring back a piece of the ooze.
Unknown: That would be cool.
Unknown: Right?
Kenzo: And then you could run some tests on it.
Delwath: And we could run some tests.
Unknown: Mm. Love it.
Unknown: Right?
Seeker: Love it. And then, then show it to the mirror.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I wanna show the fucking ooze to the mirror.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Like that's gotta... That's gonna be fun.
Delwath: Because actually, we could...
Delwath: Why are we not just...
Delwath: Well, hold on. Here's an even better idea.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: teleport back to Vintasharna.
Delwath: We'll r- take a piece of dirt from right here,
Unknown: right?
Unknown: Ah.
Delwath: Then teleport back to Vintasharna.
DM: You can't rainbow bridge. It takes seven days to recharge.
Delwath: Oh, we already used our rainbow bridge.
Delwath: Never mind. It's not gonna work.
Unknown: Forget it.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Nah, it's fine. We'll just fly.
Unknown: Stick together.
Unknown: Okay, let's do it. Let's do it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, green dragon and Kenzo.
Unknown: The poison immune bunch.
DM: Delweth turned into a dragon. Yes.
Unknown: [clapping]
Seeker: Now only, only Wellby needs to become a dragon.
Delwath: Are you sure you don't wanna be a dragon sometime?
Wellby: I mean, I would love to be.
Kenzo: Th- this is actually kind of a cool thing to be a dragon for is this.
Wellby: Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Unknown: You know?
DM: But only one of you.
Wellby: I would burn that...
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: I can only tel- t- polymorph one person at a time.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: But tomorrow-
Unknown: Oh, wait. So you've been a dragon twice.
Wellby: Is it, uh... Is it concentration?
Unknown: No, no, no.
Unknown: I'm riding the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Polymorph?
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Wellby: I mean-
Unknown: No, don't worry. It's just-
Wellby: That's what I'm assuming
Unknown: ... yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, we're, we're, we're gonna have better perception-
Unknown: We're social circles and everything
Wellby: ... in our forms too.
Unknown: Share, equal out our perception.
Delwath: That's a good idea. No, no, no, no.
Delwath: You know what? I should... I'm...
Delwath: Nope, change of plan. Sorry.
Delwath: Uh, Wellby's gonna be the dragon.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: Right? Because then Delweth won't take any...
Delwath: Like I can maintain concentration.
Unknown: Perfect.
Delwath: Right? Now, here's another question.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: And you-
DM: How fast can a dragon fly?
Unknown: Well,
Unknown: uh-
Wellby: So fast.
Unknown: [laughs] It's really fast.
Delwath: The, the other question here is...
Delwath: Okay, hold on. I'm gonna ask you.
Delwath: A dragon can fly... A green dragon can fly 80.
Delwath: Right? So is that close? Are we gonna...
Delwath: But you don't have to go to-
Wellby: Uh, I lose items in polymorph?
Wellby: Do I retain class abilities like-
Delwath: No. You retain no abilities.
Delwath: You attain your personality alignment.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: That's it.
Wellby: But I have wings.
Delwath: Um, but you can fly-
Delwath: 'Cause you're a fucking dragon.
Wellby: Sweet.
Delwath: Um, but the...
Delwath: We don't have to go to the center.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: They're just trying to find a point where there is ooze.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: They're just trying to get to the surface
DM: Right, but you have to get, you have to go 14 miles into the storm to get to the edge of the city.
Wellby: That's right.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Or it's not quite that. It's-
Unknown: So-
DM: ... 13 and a half to the center. You have to go 13 miles into the storm.
Delwath: So let's figure out how far.
DM: So you can go 800 feet a minute.
DM: [dice rolling]
Delwath: So let's figure out how, and then there's a, I have a question about, um-
Wellby: Wait, why is the time no problem though?
Delwath: 'Cause it's-
DM: So that's nine miles per hour.
DM: You're not gonna make it.
Wellby: That's hilarious.
DM: I mean, you'll be permanently a dragon.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: How many times can you cast it?
Delwath: Just once, but h- but hold on.
Delwath: You can't... Isn't it until dispelled?
DM: Yeah, you, somebody, Seeker could dispel it.
Delwath: Can I just dispel it?
DM: No, y- you need to-
Wellby: You need to dispel magic
DM: ... dispel means somebody needs to cast dispel magic.
Delwath: No, I know, I know, but can I just cast dispel magic-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... and it's a dispel?
DM: But you don't auto succeed.
DM: It's a ninth level spell, so you have to beat the ability check.
DM: Unless you cast it with a ninth level slot, which you don't have.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Seeker could cast dispel magic with a ninth level slot.
DM: Or I could cast it with this and then I would auto succeed with dispel magic.
Wellby: That's like bardic inspiration.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Like we, you know this a-
Delwath: Are you okay with this, like [laughs] are you okay with this?
Seeker: This is the risk of permanent dragon.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: The question is, am I okay with permanently being a giant green dragon?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yes. [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Wellby: You should be asking am I okay changing back to a halfling again.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: I mean, um-
Seeker: I mean, I can, I can attest it's an issue.
DM: A-
Seeker: The changes are jarring, yeah
Delwath: ... as we, I believe gre- I mean, can't green dragons shapeshift?
DM: But you'll never, you, you have to dispel it in order to get your class abilities back.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: You could shapeshift into a human, but you'd just be a human.
DM: You would never be-
Wellby: Well, I can be, I could shapeshift to a halfling.
DM: You can be a halfling.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Okay. Anyway, if you're okay being a dragon, right, we could just dispel it when you're back.
Delwath: It's fine. No big deal.
Wellby: You don't say that in a way that gives me a great deal of confidence.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] No, it'll work.
DM: It'll work.
Delwath: No, it'll definitely work.
Wellby: Huh. Look, it's fine. Okay.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, let's do it.
Unknown: Let's do it.
DM: Okay. So Wellby turns into a dragon.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Kenzo mounts on the back of the dragon.
Unknown: Yes. All
Delwath: And you begin flying into the ash.
Unknown: [laughs] Yes.
Unknown: A- a-
Wellby: Kenzo, I've, I've had this dream so many times, Kenzo.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Faster.
DM: K- both of you immune to poison.
Kenzo: Well, I'm an astral, I'm an astral monk on you.
DM: Well, that only lasts an hour.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: The astral form.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: Right? As, and it's gonna take you an hour and a half to get to the edge of the city.
Unknown: All right. I'll, I'll wait till we get closer.
DM: So wait till you're a little closer.
DM: Um, the sun is also setting,
DM: so you can see the, the, like
DM: lines of the sunset stretching across, um, the ash cloud from the outside, which is now...
DM: I mean, you guys, you two s- um, Delwath and Seeker are, like, you have the, you have to retreat a bit 'cause the ash is growing stronger, so.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: Um,
DM: you fly 13 miles, an hour and a half into the storm until you get to the, like
DM: r- roughly the edge of the city.
DM: There's no, there's no real marker.
DM: And now this is where the storm is super intense.
DM: Neither of you, I forgot that you're immune to poison, so neither of you have to make con saves because you're both immune to poison.
DM: Um,
DM: and the,
DM: uh, so as you, so as you get, like, there's no obvious marker that this is the edge of the city or anything.
DM: Um-
Wellby: But I-
Delwath: No, but I can read the terrain.
DM: Okay. Yeah.
Wellby: Like the sweep of the-
DM: Well, right. I mean, your visibility is only-
Kenzo: Kenzo knows where the, Kenzo knows where the consciousness even is
DM: ... any, only 30 feet. Kenzo has a sense, has a memory at least of where the consciousness is, and so you begin flying
DM: around. Like, what are you looking for specifically?
Kenzo: Uh, we're, we're, we're trying to find the edge of the, uh, uh, the river bank, like that area.
Kenzo: We, we want to chop off a little bit of ooze, so we want to go, kind of go to the edge where the con- the, the edge of the, um,
Unknown: the, the eye.
DM: Sewer outlet?
Kenzo: The eye.
DM: Oh, you want to go all the way to the eye?
Kenzo: Well, just where, wherever the ooze is, the edge of the ooze.
DM: Well, there's lots of places you could find, potentially find the ooze.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: 'Cause it stretch, remember it stretches all underneath the city.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So that's why I know... I mean, the,
DM: the plaza in the middle is the easiest place, but I just want to know what you want to look for specifically.
Unknown: I mean, I think, I-
DM: Like, are you looking for a different well?
DM: Are you looking for a sewer outlet into the river?
DM: Are you just going to the plaza?
Kenzo: I, I think, I think as we're flying, we're headed...
Kenzo: Well, let's head towards the plaza.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: But as we're going, if there's any other, like, little thing where it looks like there's a bit of ooze that's coming out-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... then we, we can stop there. We're, our, this is mission collect ooze.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: That's, that, that's our mission right here.
DM: So-
Wellby: Look for wells
DM: ... make a, make a perception check with disadvantage because you're, it's heavily s- it's obscured.
Wellby: Uh, do I have advantage with the bow?
Delwath: You have blind sense though.
Wellby: That cancels the disadvantage?
DM: No, 'cause you can't use equipment in dragon form.
Delwath: Ah, but, but you have... Does blind sense help?
Delwath: Blind sense can see through obscured things.
DM: Oh, does the dragon have blind sense?
Delwath: Dragon has 60 foot blind sense and 120 foot-
DM: Okay, so-
Wellby: It's still above 25
DM: ... straight roll. Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: right, I guess, well,
DM: yeah, yeah. Well, right.
DM: You get your dragon's bonus, not the...
DM: You don't have reliable talent or your-
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Oh, that would be-
Wellby: Do I add my proficiency bonus?
DM: Nope.
Delwath: Uh, you add the dragon's, which is the same as yours.
Wellby: Does someone have that handy?
Delwath: Yeah, I got it, I got it. Perception plus 12.
Wellby: Uh, that's a 23 with the worst of two rolls.
DM: Okay. So as you're, as you're approaching,
DM: um, you do see, like, you sense with your blind sense because you can sort of, um, sense the layout of the ground below you as you're, you're approaching.
DM: There's not, there's not a well that you pass, but you see like a, there's like a collapsed well basically that once was a well but that's fallen in-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... and there's a ring of rubble around the outside.
DM: So theoretically you could
DM: try there or you could just keep going.
Wellby: Good question.
Unknown: Just try there.
Wellby: Let's do it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: So you land.
Wellby: Yes.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo senses where's the ooze.
Unknown: Touch this.
DM: It's, it's right below you.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Doesn't seem to have sensed you yet
Kenzo: There, there is a well here
DM: W- uh, yeah
Unknown: Seems like a-
DM: It's like partially full of rubble
Wellby: Is it that we're gonna like sneak in and chop off a piece of the ooze and-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... bring it back?
Kenzo: Yeah. Basically, yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, okay. Well, if it's, there's rubble, that's fine.
Kenzo: K- uh, Kenzo passes through it.
DM: Okay. So Kenzo begins dropping down through the, through the rubble in the well.
Wellby: If I shape shift, do I retain my poison immunity or do I take on the, um-
Unknown: Oh, good question
Unknown: ...
Unknown: whatever I shift into?
Unknown: Uh...
DM: Uh, dragon-
Unknown: Can you-
DM: Wait, adult green dragon doesn't have shape shift
Delwath: Yeah, except we fought a green dragon and he had shape shift, which is...
Delwath: I never, I didn't actually look at the stats.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: I just assumed the dragon could shape shift.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, no, no, because the o- the,
DM: the, the old green... Yeah, yeah, fine.
DM: Dragon can shape shift.
Delwath: I, I only assumed it could shape shift because we fought a shape shifting green dragon.
DM: The...
Delwath: So m- I mean, maybe we can't.
Delwath: I just, I just was operating on the
Delwath: in world rather than stat block.
DM: Right. But not every green dragon has the same abilities.
Unknown: No, no, that's-
Unknown: It's true. It's true
Unknown: ... yeah, it's fair.
Unknown: Yep
Delwath: Totally fair.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: I, I just... That's why I said it could shape shift.
Unknown: I, I-
Wellby: Yeah, I think there's something exciting to Kenzo going alone.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Kenzo-
DM: Kenzo drops down through the,
DM: um, through the-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... through the rubble, and you s- you come to what looks like,
DM: um, a
DM: p- a,
DM: a partially collapsed
DM: cistern, right? Like, it seems like there was, um...
DM: What is that? There's that place in
DM: Istanbul I wanna see, that say there's that-
Unknown: Oh, look.
Seeker: It's the, um, Medusa heads. It's up, there's like an upside down Medusa head inside the Basilica Cistern.
Unknown: It's called the-
DM: Yeah, yeah. The Basilica Cistern
Seeker: ... crazy fucking place.
DM: That's what I'm,
DM: that's what I'm, uh...
DM: So I don't know if you guys know this.
Unknown: I don't know it. Describe it.
DM: So the Basilica Cistern is a massive cistern, um,
DM: that was built in
DM: Constantinople-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... in the, in the 3rd to 4th century, and was like a huge...
DM: It's like a giant underwater, underground cistern-
Unknown: It is
DM: ... that's like has all sorts of rows of, um, like columns and pillars and, um, it l- it looks super cool from the pictures.
DM: Um, and that's basically what is beneath Isengai,
DM: or at least this part of Isengai.
DM: It's this massive underground
DM: cistern with wells that go to, that drop down into it from different parts of the city,
DM: and f- clearly fed by the river.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Um,
DM: and you see that...
DM: But it's, but it, like a lot of it has collapsed.
DM: So while once in the heyday of Isengai it would've been this massive open space, now like there's just c- collapsed ceilings and limes.
DM: So it's not actually a sewer system that the ooze lives in.
DM: It's the, the network that's created by the piles of rubble that now block large parts of the cistern-
Unknown: Ooh, wow
DM: ... creating a maze.
DM: But you see below you, um, two small, two like tendrils of greenish purple, um,
DM: ooze like substance
DM: that turn and see you, and leap to attack.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: How's it going down there, Kenzo?
Kenzo: Oh, so far so good. Initiative?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: 24.
DM: Yeah, you beat them.
Seeker: Um, Kenzo will, uh...
Kenzo: Yeah, Kenzo will, 'cause this is, this is m- mission capture ooze, so, um,
Kenzo: he's gonna try to, um,
Kenzo: like literally just go and, I don't know if it's grappling or what it would be, but like he literally wants to go and just with magic hands like tear some of these off.
DM: So,
DM: so grapple, I mean, if you stun one you could just like grab it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, you could try grappling and then use a, like an object interaction to try and rip a piece off.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Soul sight it first?
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Soul sight. Thank you.
Kenzo: Soul sight first then.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Soul sight first.
DM: [laughs] Okay. So-
Unknown: [laughs] Is it friendly?
DM: No, it's not friendly. Um, the-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... the ooze is...
DM: Um, I don't know how to-
Seeker: There's some pictures there, but
DM: I'm trying to figure out the best way to actually do this.
DM: Um-
Seeker: This is my picture of the upside down Medusa head.
Kenzo: What?
Seeker: And there is this, like interior cistern.
Unknown: Oh, I can imagine.
Seeker: Yeah. It's just a crazy place.
Kenzo: Those things are so cool.
Seeker: It's all dark. There's just like an exten- expansive puddle, so like a football field-
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... and there's just ancient columns and-
Seeker: ... rows going on forever.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I'm like-
Unknown: It's crazy. [laughs]
Wellby: ... ancient civil engineering is amazing.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So,
DM: um,
DM: the...
DM: So here, here's how soul sight's gonna work, because each part of the ooze is also, has different stat blocks.
Unknown: Oh, my gosh.
DM: So you're gonna get-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... a little bit of information about this part of ooze and a little bit of information about the whole, the basic ooze.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, so this, this, uh,
DM: um,
DM: purple pseudopod
DM: is CR nine.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Resistant to acid,
DM: immune to blinded, charmed, deafened, exhausted, pranked, and prone, prone.
DM: Um,
DM: bad at charisma, good at strength.
DM: Um, this is a small piece of the actual ooze itself, and you get just like one piece of information about the full ooze from soul sighting
DM: a segment. So what do you want to know about the full ooze?
DM: One of the things. Resistances, immunities, strongest save, weakest save, or CR.
DM: You can pick one.
Unknown: Immunities.
Seeker: Weakest save.
DM: Well, pick one.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Life story.
Kenzo: Well, we're gonna get that once we, uh, show it to Mir.
Wellby: Closest friends.
Unknown: Deepest fear.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Favorite movies.
Kenzo: [laughs] Um, yeah, I'll go with, I'll go with immunities.
Wellby: Favorite date.
DM: Acid, necrotic, poison damage.
DM: Charmed, exhausted, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, and unconscious.
Kenzo: That sounds like one of those, like, uh...
Kenzo: It's like, uh, Joseph's multicolored code or something.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Th- those are all of its immunities?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Read them again.
Seeker: Are there things it's not immune to, Jesus?
DM: Uh-
Wellby: That'd be quicker [laughs]
DM: ... yeah, actually, I don't think there's any conditions it's not immune to.
Wellby: Oh, it's immune to all the conditions.
DM: Uh, incapac- It's not immune to incapacitated.
Kenzo: It can't be blind, it can't be tripped.
DM: It's immune to prone.
Wellby: It's too big to be tripped.
DM: It's immune to charmed, exhaustion, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, unconscious.
Delwath: So yeah, it's basically immune to all conditions.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: And-
Delwath: What kind of damage? Acid
DM: ... acid, necrotic, and poison damage.
Kenzo: Okay, cool. I, uh, I, uh, attack it and take a bit of it.
DM: Okay, make an attack roll.
Seeker: Just wanna, like, smack a piece of it off with their staff.
Kenzo: Uh, I've got magic hands. Let's try to, like, break a, break a piece off.
Seeker: Just scoop out a chunk.
Unknown: Plus 13.
Kenzo: Oh, actually maybe I'll, maybe I'll hit it with my staff first.
Unknown: I'll try to break a piece off-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... with my staff. So plus 15.
Unknown: Uh, 27.
DM: Yeah, that hits.
Kenzo: Now what do I do? Can I... How can I, like-
DM: So, well, if you wanna, if you wanna actually break a piece off, you have to first grapple it and then rip it in, rip the piece in half.
DM: I was just suggesting earlier, if you stun it, it will automatically fail.
DM: You'll automatically be able to grapple it.
Kenzo: All right. So then I, then I, uh, I, I stun it.
Unknown: I try to stun it.
DM: Okay. So it needs to make a DC 20 con save.
DM: That is a 16.
Unknown: It fails.
DM: So it is stunned.
Unknown: Great.
Kenzo: And now I can...
DM: I mean, you can flurry your blows, so s- grappling is an unarmed attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So just make an unarmed attack.
DM: You have advantage on the attack roll.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Unknown: Uh...
Unknown: Uh, oh.
Delwath: Don't you have a plus 14 now?
Unknown: Uh, 19?
DM: 19 hits.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So you grapple it, and then just as a, because it's stunned, as a free object interaction, you can rip a piece off.
Kenzo: Perfect. Great, and now I will, uh, disengage and run.
Delwath: But you don't have any actions.
Unknown: No.
DM: You used your bonus action. You can just run, but it's stunned, so it can't do anything to you.
Kenzo: Okay, perfect. I get out of there.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Nice. Good job. See, you didn't really need the guide.
DM: So you run.
Unknown: We did not let the guide.
DM: There's this-
Unknown: [laughs] Great.
Wellby: Sweet
DM: ... this... So as you pull the piece of the ooze off, it hardens into crystal.
Wellby: Ooh.
Unknown: Crystal.
Unknown: That's cool.
Unknown: Okay, great.
DM: And then you flee back up the tunnel, or the collapsed well, away from the-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... ruined cistern.
Kenzo: And then I hop back on Wellby's back, and then we fly back to the, where everybody else is.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: And then the dispel does not work, and Wellby stays a green dragon forever.
Wellby: [laughs] The end.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Well, I mean-
Wellby: Has it been an hour?
DM: Oh, it's been more than an hour.
Unknown: How's it feel, Wellby?
DM: It's been, it's been three hours.
Seeker: Life choices right now. [laughs]
Kenzo: Well, Wellby, what, are, what, like, what's, uh, what do you think now that you've had the experience?
Wellby: Uh, I mean, the flying part feels pretty normal.
Wellby: It's the, uh, it's just the size.
Wellby: Like, I, I should be able to fit through things and I can't.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Pretty different, right?
Wellby: Like, I can touch both sides of the deck at the same time.
Wellby: I'm confused by that.
Unknown: I, I know what you're talking about.
Unknown: Look at this. Look at this.
Wellby: Pretty great.
Unknown: I just-
Wellby: I'm touching both
Seeker: ... I just had that yesterday and it was so weird.
Kenzo: Pretty great. Yeah. I mean...
Seeker: [sighs] If only we all could feel that.
Unknown: Ow, it feels like a new dragon.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Totally.
Seeker: Well, I guess there's no way.
Wellby: It's been a good run though. I feel ready to go back to being-
Unknown: Halfling
Wellby: ... a halfling again.
Unknown: All right.
Kenzo: Can you cast a spell magic, or was that it?
Seeker: Well, I can still-
Unknown: I mean-
DM: Anybody can
Wellby: ... have some real, like, like, dysphoria.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Wing dysphoria
Delwath: ... dis- to dispel an nth level spell though, you have to roll a 14 or higher.
Delwath: Just assuming, assuming you have a plus 5.
DM: Yeah, you have, you'd have to roll a 14 or higher with dispel magic.
Seeker: And there's just this one
Unknown: chance every-
Unknown: No.
DM: Oh, no. You add half your...
DM: Or no. Yes, 14 or higher.
DM: Right.
Delwath: I mean, I could auto succeed by casting glob this.
DM: You can just... I mean, it's a third level slot.
DM: You can just try a few times, and if it doesn't work you can use a fourth level slot and then a fifth level s-
Unknown: Oh.
DM: I mean, you're planning on resting, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So.
Delwath: Yeah. But if we're planning on resting, I should just do glob this.
DM: Do glob this. Yeah.
Delwath: I'll just, I'll just...
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Delwath will just dispel it. Well-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... I'll try... Nah, I'll just do that.
Wellby: You auto, you auto succeed.
Unknown: I'll just do that.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay. I'll auto succeed.
Unknown: We show the, uh, uh-
Wellby: Ooh
Unknown: ... ooze to Beryl.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Amazing.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Now what's our question?
DM: What's your question?
Delwath: Um, wait, wait. First, is it a creature of Limbo?
Delwath: My sword can detect creatures of Limbo.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Sword
DM: ... n- no.
Unknown: No.
DM: Well, hmm.
DM: No, it is not a creature.
Unknown: But-
DM: It is not a native, it is not native to Limbo.
Seeker: That it turned into crystal is very interesting, because that's the antithesis of Limbo.
Seeker: Crystal is the kind of epitome of order, isn't it?
DM: True.
Seeker: So maybe it's a corrupted creature from...
Seeker: What's the plane of order called?
Unknown: Machinus?
Unknown: Machanis.
Seeker: Maybe it's a sort of, like, imprisoned victim of the war against Machanis thousands of years ago.
Seeker: That has been limbo-fied.
Seeker: Anyway, why would it turn into crystal?
Unknown: It's odd.
Wellby: That is odd.
Delwath: It is odd.
Seeker: Or maybe that's just a collapsed state of limbo entities where
Seeker: organized matter from the material plane
Seeker: turns into Ooze when it dies,
Seeker: and Ooze when it dies turns into something perfectly organized.
Unknown: That's the reverse-
Wellby: There's something to that
Seeker: ... right, reverse entropy state from its living state.
Kenzo: Tim, uh, once I pull the piece of Ooze off, is the piece of Ooze I have now kind of inoperculous?
DM: In your hand? No.
Unknown: It's, it's like dead.
DM: Dead, yeah.
Wellby: Look.
Seeker: Is it a black opaque crystal or...?
DM: It's more like sort of purple gray.
DM: Like purpley with grayer swirly streaks.
Unknown: Amethysty?
DM: S- sort of amethysty, but dull.
DM: It doesn't have that, it doesn't...
DM: It's not like-
Unknown: It's not magical?
DM: Well, not only that it's not magical, it's that it, it feels a little, it looks a little desaturated.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like it's not, it's not the sort of vibrant sort of bright gemstone.
DM: It's a
DM: grayish purple sort of desaturated hue.
Seeker: Is there any arcane meaning to
Seeker: grayish purple desaturated crystal?
DM: N- no.
Kenzo: All right. Let's show it to the mirror.
Wellby: Yep.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And we ask it, um,
Kenzo: we ask it what it, what's its story?
Unknown: How to beat it?
Kenzo: What are your, what's its weaknesses?
Wellby: How, like how did it come to being and grow?
Wellby: Like...
Delwath: I mean, the story of its growth?
Kenzo: Well, we kind of wanna know two things. I mean, we wanna know its story just for fun and just for plot, but we also really wanna know how to kill it.
Wellby: Well, but I'm thinking that too, like maybe knowing how it came into being offers some-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... clues as to-
Delwath: I think its origins will offer clues
Wellby: ... undoing.
Delwath: 'Cause the mirror doesn't tell us, like...
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Strategies.
DM: Strategies.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Okay. All right. Yeah. Yeah.
Seeker: I, I think the story of, uh, its life.
Kenzo: Tell us how you came to be. Tell, tell us how you came to be.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Make a wisdom check.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Plus six.
Seeker: And the most exciting-
Wellby: Wait, what's this?
Unknown: ...
Unknown: attack on the sky ship that he's ever heard.
Wellby: Is it a plus a billion?
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: No, it's just a straight wisdom check, just wisdom plus your wisdom mod, so plus six.
DM: 19.
Unknown: 19.
DM: Okay, that's good. Um, so you hold it up to the mirror.
Wellby: Yo.
DM: And you watch as the
DM: image in the mirror turns briefly black, and then
DM: you see
DM: below you,
DM: uh, sort of looking up just one sort of, uh, circle of light above, the sun shining down into a, uh, dark-
Unknown: Which sun?
DM: The, the material plane sun.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Shining down into a, um,
DM: y- you can see like ripples in the water, right?
DM: So you're... It's like looking down into this cistern below Isingue, uh, but when it is less ruined.
DM: And then there's a
DM: viol- like the, everything starts shaking like an earthquake and, but instead of things falling down, there's like
DM: things that jut out that are shooting out from the ground, like pieces of stone.
DM: Water is like solidifying and shooting up as a spike of solid water.
DM: The s- some of the stones are beginning to like decay at the bottom and melt and like flow out across, like liquid stone across the surface.
Kenzo: Sounds pretty, sounds, sounds pretty limbo.
Wellby: This is the ruination.
Seeker: Yeah, this is good.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And then, um, there's a,
DM: uh,
DM: the wa- the water itself in the...
DM: Oh, that's a detail I forgot to mention.
DM: So there's, there was essentially, you saw essentially no water in the cistern.
Wellby: Mm. Mm. Mm.
DM: You didn't actually see any water down below.
Wellby: Mm. Mm. Mm. Oh, shit.
DM: The wa- you see, you see like a,
DM: a dark,
DM: uh, swirling mass of s- like liquid stone and,
DM: uh,
DM: I don't know how to describe it. Like threads.
DM: Like, like if you took, if you took a, if you took like a bunch of gummy bears and, or sorry, gummy worms and microwaved them slightly so they're all like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... stuck together into a-
Unknown: Gelatinous mass
DM: ... gelatinous mass.
DM: Be- nucleates in the center of the water underneath the cistern.
DM: [phone ringing]
Kenzo: This is so crazy. I haven't heard a phone ring in like
Unknown: 20 years.
DM: Um.
Unknown: You guys sh-
DM: No.
Unknown: I don't think we can answer that.
DM: It's always spam.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Okay. [laughs] Yeah.
Delwath: If it was like somebody who needs to reach David Kong or something.
DM: Right. Um, and then this gelatinous mass, uh,
DM: hardens into solid stone.
DM: Yeah, it's all spam. And then, and then like, um,
DM: it, the like nearest bit of the water begins to like solidify into jelly, and you watch over time as more and more bits of the water underneath
DM: Isingue, like little filaments will form stretching out across the water and like solidify and crystallize and nucleate along that filament emerging from this,
DM: this mass at the center which then begins to spin and actually splits into two that are connected by some wire, like orb- orbiting
DM: around each other with like, as they spin s- throwing off more and more little filaments that land further in the water, and then a line of like gelatinous mass
DM: like nucleates along the line.
Seeker: Oh, boy. So like this is two-
DM: There's two of these like solid masses of microwaved gummy worms-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... that have solidified and turned into some kind of weird s-
Delwath: What is that muttering about?
Unknown: I don't know.
Unknown: Um
Unknown: Still talking.
Unknown: The-
DM: And spinning around each other and as they spin they're throwing off more little bits that nucleate into another...
Kenzo: Yeah, so yeah. So th- this is totally gonna like, like...
Kenzo: Th- this is literally, um, the fucking...
Kenzo: It's the great, it's the great use.
Kenzo: The, the, the, uh, nanotechnology dude-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... the thing.
DM: Oh, yeah
Unknown: The great use.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: This is literally the-
Delwath: But we only detected one...
DM: Well,
DM: I mean-
Delwath: It could have c- collapsed together, yeah
DM: ... yeah, or like there's two, there's two nodules orbiting around each other but they're one-
Unknown: Spot, spot, right
DM: ... spot, right. Like-
Kenzo: But the, but the thing that it's, it's, it's, it's, it's water that's like causing it to...
Kenzo: It's like infecting water and then-
DM: Yeah, it's infecting all of the water underneath Isengai.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: And then all of that is like solidifying and drawing in, and you watch...
DM: Like time is sped up in the mirror, right?
DM: So you watch over time-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... as more and more of these...
DM: And then the first like maybe years later there's the first like little...
DM: It's slow. It's a slow process.
DM: The, you know... Uh, the first little tendril creeps up out of a-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... out of a well and like begins to feel around.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right? And at this point that you can see in the mirror, right?
DM: Isengai is much more intact, but over time it begins to corrode and destroy all of the...
DM: It seems to actually eat the stone somehow.
DM: It's like acidically corroding all of the stone in the city as it slowly grows over years.
DM: I mean, it's been growing for a quite a long time.
Unknown: Okay. All right.
DM: And that's what you see.
Unknown: So-
Wellby: What does that suggest for how to destroy it?
Delwath: Find that little nodule thing, right?
Wellby: Right.
Delwath: I mean, it's the plan Kenzo suggested at the very beginning.
Delwath: Find its center and then-
Wellby: Starting point.
Unknown: I mean...
Delwath: Like we know where it is, we just have to fight our way...
Delwath: I mean, the naive thing is we fight our way to the nodule and then we
Delwath: do something clever.
Seeker: Well, what would be cool is if there was a way to like...
Kenzo: If there was like an antidote.
Kenzo: Like what's the anti-limbo antidote to like kind of decontaminate it, like the bioremediation strategy.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: But like-
Delwath: To like, like cause it to shrink and draw back and-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... retreat out of the city somehow.
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
Kenzo: That would be cool.
Kenzo: The dumber thing feels like we just like go and drop a nuke.
Delwath: But like do we try and,
Delwath: do we try and like
Delwath: make it withdraw into itself and get smaller, and smaller, and smaller, or do we just go kill the brain?
Kenzo: Uh, yeah, 'cause it's like how do we get down to the bottom of the...
Kenzo: Where the, the third, the, the third one thing.
Kenzo: That, that... The, it's the one at the, the very bottom that's like the, you know-
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... probably the main one.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: I mean...
Wellby: It grew up in the sewer?
DM: Well, the cistern.
Unknown: The cistern.
Wellby: The cistern. Maybe it doesn't like light.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Like maybe it wants to be in the dark.
Delwath: I think it, I think it likes the water.
Delwath: It's more water. Yeah.
Delwath: I think it's more that it spread...
Delwath: This may be slightly cheating, but I...
Delwath: The water of, of
Delwath: Isengai, I think it spread along.
DM: Yeah, no, you knew that from the Heartroot.
Delwath: Right. Okay, wait. We knew the water was magical.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: So can like we starve it of its water somehow?
Seeker: Or, or desiccate it in that idea?
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Like maybe with heat we can dry it out.
Delwath: I think it's...
Delwath: Doesn't it... Isn't the water all gone now?
DM: The water's all gone, but there's clear...
DM: There was a... Kenza sensed a concentration in the river.
DM: The river is not dry.
Delwath: Oh, maybe we go kill the river one.
Seeker: And then it, and then it will no longer have a source of water.
Delwath: It disconnects it from the magic.
Delwath: Maybe that's how we bioremediate it, right?
Delwath: In other words, if it's-
Kenzo: Mm, yeah. All right, let's do that
Delwath: ... if it's growing from the...
Delwath: And the nice thing about the water one-
Unknown: Outside
Delwath: ... outside, and also like, I mean, I don't want to copy Seeker, but two leviathans?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Two leviathans.
Delwath: Water creatures?
Seeker: Good movement speed in the, in the river.
Seeker: Interesting point you're making.
Kenzo: Let's do it. Let's go kill the river one.
Delwath: Like there's a certain appeal in like let's...
Delwath: Like we could like go after it in the river and then-
Kenzo: Let's do it. Long rest and then what are we doing?
Kenzo: Are you making another Seeker? Are we doing a Hero's Feast?
Wellby: Yeah, load up all the things.
Delwath: Load up all... You can only do one.
Seeker: Probably Hero's Feast.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, no.
Delwath: Oh, no, 'cause you can't take Hero's Feast as a spell.
DM: Right.
Seeker: So what did I end up taking?
Unknown: I think I-
Delwath: You took Demiplane
Unknown: ... Oh.
Delwath: So you can only Hero's Feast by casting Wish.
Unknown: So...
Delwath: You can still cast Hero's Feast as Wish.
Unknown: [mumbles]
Delwath: Didn't you take Demiplane?
Unknown: Um...
Wellby: That's what we talked about.
Unknown: We talked about taking Demiplane.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, you're right.
Kenzo: Well, that's, that's what we all suggested, but I don't know if Eric chose it.
Seeker: Quickly not happening.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But, I mean, if you had Hero's Feast you could do a Simakrum and Hero's Feast.
Unknown: But-
DM: Well, the down- the biggest downside to a Simakrum is it takes 12 hours to cast which means that-
Delwath: Not unless you cast it with Wish
DM: ... unless you cast it with Wish.
Wellby: And then that's the Wish.
Seeker: Is there some reason to think that would be especially helpful?
Unknown: Simakrum?
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: No, only like
Delwath: it's, it's a good... It's your last opportunity for a Seeker 7.
Delwath: Well, Seeker 7 can come with us in frame.
DM: No. Seeker 7 can come with you to Plane of Fire.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I, I think Hero's Feast.
DM: It's gonna be tough if you're all constantly poisoned.
Delwath: It... Hero's Feast is definitely-
DM: Poison gives you disadvantage on all attacks
Unknown: ... yeah.
Seeker: So I, I use Wish to cast Hero's Feast and then you're immune to poison.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Then you're immune to poison for 24 hours.
DM: So you cast it right before you go to bed, so then you're impun- immune to poison all the next day.
Unknown: Right. And I get my Wish slot back.
DM: And you get your Wish slot back, yeah.
Delwath: Let's do that. Perfect. And I mean, I guess if you didn't want to use Wish, but I don't think Seeker 7 is your best option for...
Delwath: Like you're probably better are using Wish to turn into a leviathan or something like that, or sorry, using Shape Shift to turn into a leviathan.
Seeker: That's what I'm gonna do the next day, yeah.
DM: Yeah
Delwath: But I mean, I'm, I'm pretty tempted to do the same thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: If we're going in the river-
Unknown: Yeah, we're going in the river
Delwath: ... there, there's something to be said for...
Delwath: Especially it's not, if there's no creatures of limbo here so I don't get 4d8 damage, I only get 2d8 damage.
DM: Right.
Delwath: It makes, uh...
DM: So
DM: here Seeker, as the sun sets you set up camp.
DM: Seeker creates a feast for you,
DM: and you
DM: consume the feast. Roll 2d10, everybody gets 2d10 added to your hit point maximum.
Delwath: Can you stack that with Aid, by the way?
DM: There's... Yeah, no reason not.
DM: They're different spells.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: No, Seeker rolls 2d10-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... for everybody. Everybody gets the same amount.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: 11.
Unknown: Solid.
DM: So everybody adds 11 to their hit point maximum.
DM: [coughs]
DM: We're not in Vindrasharna though, right?
DM: You're not in Vindrasharna.
Delwath: We could be though, right?
Seeker: Wait, where, where is it?
Unknown: Where is it?
Unknown: Seeker has two teleports.
Kenzo: Is this temporary points or is this-
DM: No
Unknown: ... total hit points, maximum?
DM: It's, you go to the, um...
Unknown: He says it will-
Delwath: Oh, right. If we long rest in Vindrasharna-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... we can get a billion and a half.
DM: [coughs] 10 HP.
Unknown: It's the max HP modifier, right?
DM: But that's, if you're planning on polymorphing-
Unknown: There's probably more stuff over on Max HP
DM: ... that's mostly useless usually because they go away the minute you polymorph.
Unknown: Oh, that's true. [coughs]
Seeker: It must be the max HP modifier.
DM: Max H- set max HP modifier to 11.
Unknown: To 11.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And then actually set it to everybody-
Unknown: You get 20 more?
Delwath: Gets 20 more except somebody.
DM: I guess Seeker normally doesn't get the extras from Aid.
DM: So
DM: Wellby and Kenzo-
Unknown: So 30
DM: ... set it to 31.
Unknown: And Delwath.
DM: And Delwath.
Seeker: Nice, nice.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: And you are-
Seeker: It's like, okay, I said that'll make it interesting.
Wellby: I'll get there in a minute. Please
DM: ... you are immune to the frightened and poisoned conditions.
DM: You have resistance to poison damage.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: I think we did the right thing.
Unknown: And now we-
DM: Are you changing your sword?
Delwath: ... fish. Oh, yes I am changing my sword.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: probably to
Unknown: Arborea.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: I think, I think,
Unknown: um-
DM: Mechanist and Arborea
Delwath: ... I think Mechanist and Arborea 'cause Pandemonium is not likely to be useful.
DM: Pandemonium gives you-
Unknown: Psychic damage
DM: ... no, immune, ignore resistance to slash damage.
Delwath: Oh, that could be useful actually.
Delwath: Um, actually
Delwath: I might do that instead.
Delwath: I'm gonna do that.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: It also gives me advantage on saving throws against possession, so that's not way off base.
DM: [coughs] Yes. [coughs] Okay.
DM: So
DM: the morning comes.
DM: Uh, the a- you've, you set up camp about a mile from the ash storm, and it's now spread
DM: so that the edges of the storm are l- are lapping up against your tents.
Unknown: Oh boy.
DM: As you wake from the, a nice rest, refreshed with your hero's feast.
Delwath: Everybody gets hero points of inspiration.
DM: With your inspiration, your extra hit points, everything.
Unknown: Sweet.
DM: So you're now, you are now maybe 15, f- 15 miles from the
DM: plaza as the storm has grown slightly.
DM: Grew a, a couple miles over the course of the night.
DM: And where are you heading?
Unknown: River.
Seeker: Up river outside the storm.
DM: Well, the river's the... Oh, go to the river outside the storm and then travel up river till you get to-
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: That's what I was thinking.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: He has a return to Leviathan. That's cool.
Unknown: Yeah. I think, yeah.
Unknown: Sweet.
Delwath: I feel a little derivative here, but I think it's the right choice.
Seeker: I mean, it's a team effort.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: There you go.
Seeker: Two Leviathan is better than one Leviathan.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: That is a true statement.
Wellby: That's what Sang says. [laughs]
Kenzo: Can, can there be three Leviathans?
Unknown: No.
DM: No, not enough magic.
Unknown: Not powerful enough.
Wellby: Three Leviathans are not better than two Leviathans.
Unknown: Oh, I need to find-
DM: Oh, no wait, that wouldn't work
Unknown: ... Sang ghost.
DM: You do have a scroll of wish.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: There could be three Leviathans.
DM: But you can't use wish to cast a ninth level spell.
Unknown: Correct. Shit.
Seeker: Um, 341 HP.
Seeker: Wait, this must be a different Leviathan because it has a 40 foot swim.
Unknown: Is it the old, uh-
Seeker: I don't know, man. Where, where do I, where should I find the stat block?
Unknown: Tim's gonna send it to you.
DM: Yeah, let me find it.
Delwath: It has 120 foot swim, 328 hit points.
Delwath: AC 17, good wisdom and charisma saves, good strength.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Really good con, plus 10 con.
Unknown: I don't know exactly.
Unknown: Dagger.
Delwath: Actually in general pretty good saves except int saves are terrible.
DM: But you can keep your medicine.
Unknown: I guess that's-
Unknown: I think it's a little bit vague. Let's just set this down
DM: ... with shape change, yes with true polymorph, no.
Wellby: This is, this is like the, the family room.
Unknown: Exactly. Yeah, yeah. This is like-
DM: Eric, I texted it to you.
Unknown: Thank you.
Unknown: All right, now
Seeker: I'm gonna...
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, that's damage. Oh well. This is all
Kenzo: one big slight change. [laughs]
Unknown: Exactly.
Unknown: This is the-
DM: Right. In the-
Wellby: ... idea to be your own contractor
DM: ... true, true polymorph is, is worse than shape change because you can't,
DM: um,
DM: you can't speak or cast spells unless-
Unknown: Slightly
DM: ... you can speak only if the anatomy of its new form lets you speak-
Unknown: Wait, where is it?
DM: ... and you can't cast spells And you can't benefit from equipment, and you only retain your alignment and personality.
DM: So like you, you retain your,
DM: you retain your,
DM: like, mental ability to plan for those purposes.
DM: But you do not retain your mental ability scores for saving throws-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... or skills.
Delwath: And, and if the Levi- since the leviathan can't talk, I wouldn't be able to talk.
DM: You would not be able to talk, yes.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: [laughs] You know, pros and cons I guess.
Delwath: No, that's fine. I mean,
Delwath: Delwath is more the will animating.
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: It's probably more, if I would imagine, it's more like Delwath's will is still animating the creature.
DM: Right.
Delwath: So it's not like it's just gonna run amuck, but it's really a force of nature.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: It's like Delwath as force of nature, not Delwath-
DM: Whereas, where a Seeker is just a Seeker leviathan.
Unknown: Right.
DM: 'Cause you retain your mental ability scores.
Unknown: But that's okay.
Unknown: And beard.
DM: Yeah, and beard obviously.
DM: Oh, we need an... Okay, here.
DM: Might, it can be a crab leviathan.
DM: We have another-
Kenzo: Also what time did we wanna try to go watch the sunset?
Unknown: Although it's pretty cloudy now.
Delwath: Um, it is pretty cloudy, but the sunset's like at 5:45, so we should-
Unknown: Be like an hour and a half
Delwath: ... we should like give ourselves...
Delwath: We should meet at 4:45.
Delwath: Maybe a few, like 4:30.
Delwath: Like an hour and a half maybe we sort of, we sorta-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... take a break or...
DM: Yeah. That was, yeah, 4:30 is what I wanna stop so we can-
Unknown: Awesome
DM: ... we can drive down.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
DM: Okay.
DM: So we're not, I don't think we're gonna quite finish this before, but that's okay.
Unknown: No, that's-
DM: We'll do a little dinner.
Delwath: Maybe we can at least, hopefully we can at least, uh, kill the one in the river.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Delwath: Then see what happens.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Kenzo's ready.
DM: So you pass through the...
DM: Nobody has to bother making saves because-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... um, the,
DM: uh... So you're just, you're just going upriver basically, right?
Delwath: No, that's not gonna work. You can't really make it bigger.
Unknown: Oh, you can. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I've given you a challenge.
Kenzo: Well, before this is done, we'll, [laughs] we'll see how much bigger I can actually...
Kenzo: 'Cause I can see you've already pulled out something
Unknown: bigger.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So let me-
Delwath: Just a little bit
DM: ... uh... So I'll put the river like this.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. I'm moving it all.
DM: We don't need this guy.
DM: So here's like where the riverbank runs roughly.
DM: And, you know, there's a few like
DM: still remaining...
Delwath: Wait, which, um, can...
DM: This is river.
Delwath: Uh, this, the, this is the river and this is the bank.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And you're coming, you come upriver.
Unknown: Okay. That's good.
DM: And
DM: as you approach-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... so you're, you're limited to
DM: roughly-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Sorry.
Unknown: [coughs] Silly.
Kenzo: We know it's an accurate representation.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: Oh, Kenzo. Okay. [laughs]
DM: Um,
DM: so
DM: you... The visibility is only 30 feet.
DM: And as you begin to go,
DM: go upriver, um,
DM: you sense,
DM: uh,
DM: you know, Kenzo, I'm just gonna let you be sort of attuned to this condensation.
DM: And you sense that it is, it is retreating as you move until you get close to the plaza.
Kenzo: Oh, what the fuck is this?
Kenzo: Oh my God, what is happening?
Unknown: No way.
DM: Uh, when, um,
DM: lunging from
DM: the shore into the river, you see this massive shape
DM: emerging in the distance, kind of-
Delwath: Wait, where was the thing in the river?
DM: It vanished.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: They are temporary condensations in the morning.
DM: As you fly up, it re-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... it's retreating from the river, pulling back, and then
DM: leaps out at you,
DM: just condensing on the ground, rushing across the terrain here.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Wait, are we fighting this or is this the terrain?
DM: That, that's the...
Unknown: What?
Seeker: So hold on a second.
Seeker: Were, were we already leviathaned up?
Unknown: Well, presumably-
DM: You have plenty of time to do whatever you want to do here.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: So where, where are we supposed to be?
DM: Well, you're coming up the river from here.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, my God.
DM: I don't know how you're traveling.
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: Careful
Delwath: ... Wellby and Kenzo are presumably...
Delwath: Wellby can fly, right?
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: So I assume at some point we get into the river.
DM: You leviathan, you fly.
DM: Right. And we're just swimming in the river.
DM: So the two leviathans are swimming in the river.
Delwath: I mean, we might be a little further over.
Seeker: All right. So what am I gonna
Unknown: do?
DM: The-
Delwath: Where do I put all this stuff?
DM: Wellby and Kenzo...
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Just be careful. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Watch your step.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: If you f- if this falls over, Kenzo also falls prone.
DM: No.
Delwath: No, he's astral. He can't fall prone.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right. Kenzo is astral form already.
DM: Um, Wellby is-
Unknown: Wellby form
DM: ... Wellby form, but flying with your wings out from your- And you can see, you see this, your visibility is only 30 feet, so, um,
DM: uh, because of the intensity of the ash storm.
DM: So you can't actually see all of the ooze.
DM: You just see this like amorphous shape.
DM: You can see little bits of stone mixed into it.
DM: There's like sort of greenish tendrils coming out on the edges.
Wellby: I think can we like Gust of Wind it or otherwise like...
Wellby: I guess it doesn't matter.
Seeker: Well, the leviathans have a tidal wave attack.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs] Awesome.
Seeker: Which is 250 feet.
DM: And it's-
Unknown: So-
DM: You can, like it's-
Unknown: Two of these people-
DM: This is, this is like just a massive thing that's like creeping...
DM: It seems like it's creeping along
Delwath: Right, so like I'm trying to figure out, can we...
Delwath: Like the leviathan tidal wave attack is 120 feet and then goes for 250 feet.
Seeker: So we could do it from far, far away.
DM: Except you can only see 30 feet away from it.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: So you can only do it from 30 feet away.
DM: Your visibility is 30 feet because of the ash.
Seeker: Right, but we can just retreat pretty far and then send out multiple tidal waves.
Delwath: Well, it only recharges on a six, so-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... you're probably not gonna get that many unless you get lucky.
Delwath: We get two. We get two. [laughs]
Delwath: But we also have to... It can only be created,
Unknown: uh...
Delwath: Right, okay. So it,
Delwath: would probably be hard to target it until we can see the point.
Unknown: Also-
Unknown: I think it's Tim's point
Seeker: ... also there's no way for
Seeker: the humanoids to escape from it unless they're in the air, I guess.
DM: They're flying.
Unknown: They're flying in the air.
Delwath: It's up to 250 feet tall, which generally in D&D terms means you don't have to make it that big.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Right?
Seeker: We can make a two-dimensional tidal wave.
DM: Yeah, it could just be narrow.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: It, it's up to 250 feet long and up to 250 feet wide.
Delwath: It can just be, it could just be 50 by 50.
Unknown: Little tidal wave bullets.
DM: It's very strong.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
DM: Right?
Delwath: It's gonna have a good strength saving throw.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But that's okay.
DM: So
DM: what are you gonna do?
Unknown: We, we gotta-
DM: I mean, I guess you better roll initiative-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... because you, you can't see it until you're within 30 feet of it anyway.
DM: The massive ooze lurking on the shore
DM: in wait.
Delwath: What is the leviathan's initiative?
Seeker: Oh, wait, so do I use my-
Delwath: Use the leviathan
DM: The leviathans.
Unknown: 12. [dice rolling]
Unknown: 23.
Unknown: 18. [dice rolling]
Wellby: Oh.
DM: Sorry, 18... Who rolled an 18?
DM: Seeker?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 23?
Kenzo: 23 for Kenzo.
Wellby: 22 for Wellby.
DM: Mike, what did Delwath roll?
Unknown: Uh, 12.
Delwath: 13. No, 12.
Delwath: Can't do math today.
DM: Okay, so
DM: the ooze goes first,
DM: and it is going to turn, seeing you approach,
DM: slip into the water.
Unknown: We're flying.
DM: Um,
DM: yes. And then,
DM: uh,
DM: the first thing it's going to do,
DM: uh, is send
DM: pseudopod attacks
DM: against...
DM: Go, uh, the two flying creatures.
DM: So two against Kenzo. [dice rolling]
Unknown: Ooh.
DM: That's a
DM: 21 and a 25.
Kenzo: Uh, only one hits.
DM: So, uh, you take 18 points of bludgeoning.
Kenzo: Uh, deflect attack.
DM: Plus nine points of, or 11 points of acid.
DM: Go ahead and deflect.
Kenzo: And so how much is that total?
Unknown: Leviathan is so good against this.
Delwath: It's doing bludgeoning and acid.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I'm resistant to bludgeoning and immune to acid.
Delwath: I assume it's immune to acid.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Because leviathan
Kenzo: does acid damage.
Unknown: Acid damage to that one?
Seeker: Yeah, but we're not gonna use that.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 18 and...
DM: So it's like 32 total.
Kenzo: 32 total. [dice rolling] Uh, I did not cover it.
Kenzo: So I just reduce the damage by
Kenzo: 13 plus 7, 20.
Kenzo: I reduce it by 20.
DM: N- no. I don't think that's right.
DM: Don't you reduce the damage by it, plus your level?
Kenzo: Oh, a 1d10-
Unknown: 1d10 plus-
Unknown: Plus 27
Kenzo: ... 27. Ah.
Unknown: Oh,
Kenzo: that's way better. Oh, yeah, so 37.
DM: No, that damage you rolled is the damage you do when you deflect the attack.
Kenzo: Got it. Okay, yeah, so 37.
Kenzo: I, I deflected it all. Hell yeah.
Unknown: Great.
DM: Okay, so it...
DM: Are you, you're deflecting I see.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: So it has to make a dex saving throw.
Delwath: Yeah, DC 20.
DM: Fails.
Unknown: Sweet. So I just did-
DM: So what was that?
DM: What did you roll for the-
Unknown: 13, 20.
DM: 20 damage, okay.
DM: So
DM: it takes 20 damage,
DM: uh, except it's deflects...
DM: When you deflect, it does the same
DM: damage as it did, right? So it doesn't take the acid damage from its own attack.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Oh, no, wait. No, no, no, it's new damage.
DM: But what does it say?
Kenzo: Of the same type dealt by the attack.
DM: Yeah, so half of it is bludgeoning, half of it's acid.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So it only takes half. It only takes 10 damage.
Kenzo: Right. I'm, I'm tracking my heat damage.
DM: Okay.
DM: So then it's gonna make a pseudopod attack against Wellby.
DM: That's a 20 to hit.
Wellby: That just barely hits me. Yes.
DM: So you take,
DM: uh, 20 points of bludgeoning plus eight points of acid, so 28 total.
Wellby: Uh, I'll uncannily dodge that.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Is this 14?
DM: Yep.
DM: Uh, and that's gonna end his turn.
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna take a legendary action to move my move.
DM: Okay.
DM: Seeker, do you want to take a legendary action too?
Unknown: Oh, so-
DM: Oh my God, [laughs] this is gonna be ridiculous.
Seeker: Is there an advantage to...
Seeker: I say telepathically to my other leviathan friend, to us spreading out?
DM: Water good. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Ooze bad.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Kill it. Delwath only has like two intelligence right now.
Unknown: Sorry I asked.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I'll, uh,
Seeker: I'll just go right over here.
DM: So also a legendary.
Unknown: Aw.
DM: Uh, so Kenzo's up now.
DM: You are 30 feet away from the ooze, up in the air.
DM: So-
Seeker: I have a 20-foot reach.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Which would be like...
Seeker: Yeah, I'm like, you know, I'm...
Kenzo: Uh, I think I'm gonna-
DM: I assume you're like under water at the moment.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Swimming in the water.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, swimming.
Kenzo: Is this, is this in the water right now as well?
DM: It's half in the water, half out of the water.
Kenzo: Okay, cool. Yeah, I'll attack the part that's not in the water with my-
DM: Yeah, I mean, it's like 50 feet or like 80 feet across or something, so there's a lot of space you can hit.
Kenzo: Sul side first, then.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... okay.
Seeker: I might want to be further away because...
DM: So it's immune to acid damage as expected.
DM: Um, charmed, exhausted, frightened, grappled, poisoned-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... prone, restrained.
Unknown: Yeah, we get all that from-
DM: You got all that. Um-
Unknown: Resistances?
DM: Uh, no resistances.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's good at...
DM: S- strength is its best save.
DM: INT-
Unknown: [laughs] Strength
DM: ... is its worst save.
Unknown: INT is its worst?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: INT is its worst save, interesting.
DM: What else? What else you learn?
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: I never actually... This is... I never actually calculated a CR for this.
Unknown: It doesn't matter.
DM: It's a high CR.
Delwath: So it's basically immune to all conditions.
Delwath: It's, it's actually quite similar to a leviathan.
DM: It is, yeah.
Delwath: [laughs] Uh, immune to what?
Delwath: Acid and poison?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Acid and poison.
Delwath: But no resistances.
DM: No, no additional resistances-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... beyond the damage immunities.
Delwath: Okay. Kenzo's flying up to punch it.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: You should, um,
Delwath: you should bring up your half dam- half resistance.
Unknown: Yeah, um-
Unknown: Your damage resistance, I mean.
Kenzo: Yeah, so Ken- Kenzo will spend 3P on superior defense.
Kenzo: And then, um, I think it's worth it to do the, the, the langsoos claw.
Delwath: It adds a D6.
Unknown: Adds your D6, yeah.
Delwath: This could... Actually, this could stretch for a while.
Delwath: It is probably worth it.
Kenzo: All right. So I'll bonus action langsoos claw.
DM: How long does it last?
Unknown: Um-
DM: It lasts for an hour, right?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Or does it last for-
Kenzo: I think it lasts for a minute. Is it an hour?
Kenzo: Yeah, I think it's more like a minute.
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: One minute.
DM: Yeah, but that's 10 rounds. That's worth it.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. I'll do that.
DM: And then you make your staff attacks.
Seeker: So two, two staff attacks.
Unknown: Uh, no, no advantage or anything, right?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: Uh, 21 and something really high.
DM: 21 just hits.
DM: Something really high obviously hits.
Seeker: All right. So those both hit, and then
Kenzo: I do... Oh, wow, D12 plus 9.
Unknown: Okay, so now I do 3 D12.
Unknown: 3 D12 plus 18.
Kenzo: Plus 18, yeah.
Unknown: Where are the D12?
Delwath: Uh, 18 plus 18, 36.
Unknown: 36.
DM: There we go.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Uh, at the end of your turn, it will use a legendary action.
Unknown: Oh, boy.
DM: Um-
Delwath: How do you resolve two creatures trying to use a legendary action at the same time?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] Um, initiative order.
Unknown: Initiative order.
Unknown: I guess initiative order. I think it's gateways.
DM: So the ooze, ooze always beats you.
DM: Um-
Delwath: 'Cause I'm also using a legendary action
DM: ... so again, it hasn't noticed the two leviathans yet.
Delwath: Has Ken, uh... Kenzo hasn't gone yet.
Unknown: I mean-
DM: Kenza just went. Wellby is next.
Unknown: Sorry. Okay, no, I'm gonna hold my action.
DM: Uh, you... Both, uh, Kenzo and Delwath make dexterity saving-
Unknown: Wellby and Wellby.
DM: Sorry, Wellby and, and Kenzo make dexterity saving throws as a globule of acid shoots off his back and then explodes at a point in the air right about there.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: Reroll. Key
Kenzo: ... I rolled a one, but I, I'm gonna...
Kenzo: I, I can spend a key to reroll it.
DM: Yep.
Unknown: 20 for me.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 18.
DM: That does not succeed.
Kenzo: Uh, I will use a-
Unknown: Bardic inspiration
Unknown: ... bardic inspiration.
Unknown: Do we have-
DM: You don't have any
Delwath: ... do we have...
Delwath: Did we give out bardics? You probably should have given everybody a bardic.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We always give everybody a bardic.
DM: Okay, okay. Everybody has...
DM: You all have bardics.
DM: 'Cause you have, what, six total?
Unknown: I do.
DM: Yeah, so that's half.
Delwath: So everybody, each of us has one, and then-
Kenzo: Is this like roll two and then pick the highest?
DM: No, roll one.
Kenzo: No, no, it's roll one.
Unknown: Okay. Uh, 26.
DM: Okay, that succeeds.
DM: So both of you dodge out of the way of the massive burst of acid that explodes, avoiding getting drenched in dripping acidic poison ooze.
Kenzo: That sounds like a good thing that we did.
DM: And that ends its legendary action.
DM: Any other legendary actions?
Delwath: No, I'm very glad because you'll give us advantage on attacks, right?
Delwath: Wait, no, no. Uh, Eric,
Delwath: once Wellby attacks, we both should do our legendaries to do a slam attack.
DM: Oh, okay.
Delwath: Because we'll have advantage from Wellby's-
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Great.
DM: So Wellby, you're up.
Seeker: And that costs two anyway. That's okay.
DM: Correct. Um-
Wellby: The entire creature counts as one creature for the purposes of a second sneak attack.
Wellby: It's not like-
DM: Yeah, yeah, the whole-
Unknown: Kenzo is a different-
DM: Right. Yeah, no, it counts as one creature.
Wellby: Uh, reroll one.
Wellby: That's a 28 or something like that.
DM: That hits. The 21 from Kenzo hit, so.
Unknown: 21 hits.
Wellby: I think it is resistant to every single special thing that I can do.
Unknown: I think it is too.
Wellby: So I'm just gonna... Three, six, nine, 10
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 10,
Unknown: 20, 30,
Wellby: uh, 35, 43?
Unknown: 43
Unknown: Uh-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... is it resistant to lightning?
DM: Uh, nope. It's just immune to acid and poison and has no additional damage resistances.
Wellby: Uh, I may as well use the lightning arrow then.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: You know, 10 second
Wellby: at- attack, which I have-
DM: You didn't use your bonus action for anything, so...
Wellby: Yeah.
Wellby: Uh, that's high 20s again.
DM: Yep.
DM: That's a dex save.
Wellby: Uh, it is a 19 dex.
DM: Uh, it succeeds.
Unknown: Okay. Uh-
DM: Oh, wait. No-
Unknown: Oh, wait. No
DM: ... it doesn't-
Unknown: It's not a save 'cause it's the target
DM: ... 'cause it's the target.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So it doesn't, it takes the...
DM: So it's-
Wellby: So it's nine regular damage
DM: ... and 4d6 lightning.
Unknown: Yep.
Wellby: Uh, 8, 10, 15 lightning.
DM: Okay.
DM: Got it.
Unknown: Is that the end of your turn?
Unknown: That is the end of my turn.
Delwath: Okay. Tim, there's no point in rolling the acid damage, right?
Unknown: 'Cause it's immune.
DM: Yeah, it's immune to acid.
Wellby: Oh, actually, uh, I'm also...
Wellby: I'm gonna move to a place that's, like, 100 feet away from-
DM: Okay. So now you can't see it, though
Unknown: ... the ooze.
Delwath: Your visibility is only 30 feet because of the-
Wellby: Well, I'm gonna stay 30 feet...
Wellby: Oh, shit. Do we wanna stay within visual, seeing each other?
Unknown: I don't know if that matters.
Wellby: So I'm gonna stay 30 feet above it, but go, like, way to another part of it so that a single effect couldn't hit both Kenzo and I, hopefully.
Delwath: Okay. So, so you like-
Unknown: A huge-
DM: ... fly around towards the back?
Unknown: Exactly.
DM: All right. A huge
Delwath: fist materializes from the water
Delwath: and slam, punches into the ooze.
DM: [die rolling]
Seeker: Wait, how are you doing that?
DM: That's your action.
Delwath: Oh, but a 19 might miss.
DM: A 19 misses.
Unknown: No.
Seeker: Wait, that's its slam attack?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: You can do one, too.
Seeker: Uh, I'm doing that.
DM: Also a slam attack. Okay.
Unknown: Um-
DM: So now it knows you're here 'cause you're-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... slamming it.
Unknown: What do, what do I roll?
Delwath: It's... Well, you have advantage, so 2d20 and then add 14.
DM: So sorry, this is after Wellby's turn.
Seeker: Yep. 30.
Unknown: 30.
DM: Nice.
Delwath: So that hit, so it's 2d12,
Delwath: 2d12 plus 8 damage.
Wellby: I have a thing at the end of your turn I just wanna remember.
Delwath: So at the end of this turn. [die rolling]
Delwath: So 26.
DM: 26 damage?
Unknown: 26.
DM: And you're not rolling the acid, right?
Unknown: Correct.
DM: This is just the-
Delwath: Yeah, that's, that's bludgeoning.
Seeker: Just the 2d12.
Delwath: It's 4d12, including acid-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... we're, we're rolling bludgeoning. [die rolling]
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Sweet
DM: ... wait, did it use its li-
Unknown: It, it did.
Unknown: It used legendary.
Delwath: It used, it used the legendary action.
Unknown: It used a legendary action.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Got it.
Unknown: I don't know what we have.
Wellby: Wellby will say telepathically to the rest of us, "There's this tendril in back that's heading back towards the central plasma, like a, like a thing that's connecting it back to the center again."
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Let's stop that.
Unknown: Should we try and-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... cut it off?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Let's, let's, let's stop that.
Seeker: What does Del, with Leviathan say to that, say to that?
Unknown: Gargle and raw. [laughs]
Delwath: Ooze bad.
Unknown: Kill ooze.
Delwath: Hurting water. Ooze hurting water.
DM: Uh, it's Seeker's turn now, your actual turn, not your legendary.
Unknown: Pretty smart.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Um-
Kenzo: Uh, maybe I go after that?
Seeker: I'm gonna cast a-
Unknown: Wellby?
Delwath: Oh, right. You can cast.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Right.
Unknown: Pretty fast. Oh, yeah, but I have to choose between-
Unknown: Oh, is this the tendril?
Unknown: I think so
Seeker: ... it's basic- It's gonna be Rune of Psychic Destruction,
Seeker: which I will cast at...
Kenzo: This looks like a weird, like, sea urchin.
DM: Wait, you're up in the air, right?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And we're both, like-
Unknown: Like 30 or 40 feet up
Seeker: ... I will cast at, let's
Seeker: say seventh level.
Kenzo: Each one of these squares is how many?
DM: 5.
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: Oh, five.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: so that's a DC 19 int save.
DM: Int is its worst save.
DM: [die rolling] But it rolled a natural 20.
Unknown: Aw.
Unknown: So
Seeker: it's not incapacitated and then half-
Delwath: Probably half damage
Seeker: ... so it's 2d6-
DM: Divided by two
Seeker: ... um, I'll just do that here.
DM: Yeah, that's faster there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 35 divided by 2.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: 17. 17.
DM: It's razed down to 17.
Unknown: Okay. [die rolling]
DM: Uh, that, is that end of your turn?
Delwath: Uh, you get two attacks. Or no, that's a five.
Seeker: I could probably move also.
Unknown: So if I move right... Yeah,
Unknown: I'm done.
DM: Okay. Uh, it's going to now use a legendary action.
DM: Um,
DM: so it is going to drop a,
DM: uh, falling around...
DM: Well, the rest of you can't see this.
DM: Kenzo, make a dexterity saving throw.
Kenzo: Wait, Kenzo or Wellby?
Unknown: That's Wellby.
DM: Oh, Wellby in the back. [die rolling]
Unknown: 16.
DM: That fails.
Kenzo: Grog? Or, or, uh, Barik?
Wellby: Uh, I'll still only take half damage, so I'll...
Wellby: I'm gonna see how this is.
DM: Um,
DM: a, another globule of, of acid sprays, sprays towards you like a, like a fine, uh,
DM: string of nets-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... wrapping around you
DM: and you are now restrained.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: And you take, uh...
DM: The damage is poison, so you take no damage.
DM: Oh, you take a quarter damage because you are-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... as evasion plus resistance, so.
Kenzo: I feel like it's good to avoid these things.
Unknown: Yeah, they're restraining you and grabbing you.
Unknown: They're not good.
DM: So you take eight points of damage, but you are restrained Which sets your move to zero and, um, you have disadvantage on all attacks,
DM: and all attacks against you have advantage
Wellby: Is restrained the same or different from grappled?
DM: It is different from grappled
Wellby: So the advantage that I have to escape from grappled is not the same as-
DM: Does not the same as advantage or restrained
Unknown: Yeah
DM: Um, you get a save-
Kenzo: Yeah, because the g- you get knocked out, and then we have to spend-
DM: You get a new save at the end of every turn
Unknown: Yeah
DM: So at the end of your next turn, you can save to escape automatically.
DM: Who's up?
DM: Um, Delwath is up.
DM: That was the ooze's legendary, unless-
Unknown: No
DM: ... unless you want to take a... Oh, you're out of legendaries.
Delwath: Yeah, I got them back. So you can take a legendary
DM: You can take a legendary after your own turn
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: right. Yeah, yeah,
Unknown: yeah
DM: So it's very complicated with the number of legendary [laughs] actions happening
Unknown: Yeah,
Unknown: I can see
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: So I end a turn, so mine reset
Delwath: Do we think the pseudopod can be broken?
Kenzo: Yeah. You think the what?
DM: You have no idea.
Unknown: Well, I'm gonna try
Kenzo: Yeah, Ken- Kenzo's gonna fly over here too and try to break this thing off
Delwath: Right. I'm, I'm gonna send a tidal wave right here.
Delwath: Originate a tidal wave like here, and just go this way
DM: Okay
Delwath: Trying to wash away the-
DM: That's a strength saving throw?
Delwath: D- yeah, it's a DC 24 strength
DM: [dice rolling] Ah, that's a 25.
DM: So it takes half damage or what happened when it-
Unknown: No
Unknown: I'll save it takes-
DM: Can you, can you grab a bowl over there for me so I can put some chips in it?
Unknown: I sure can.
Unknown: You want these chips?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It's a crappy, crappy, crappy roll.
Unknown: 10-
DM: And this is bludgeoning?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, 10,
Delwath: mm, uh, 21.
Delwath: [laughs] Man, that's like minimum damage.
Unknown: 22.
DM: So 11 'cause it made the save?
Unknown: Yep
DM: Okay.
DM: That's certainly not enough.
DM: Whether or not the pseudopod thing-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... can be destroyed-
DM: ... that's certainly enough damage to do anything to it.
Kenzo: Dude, it should be Delwath. Delwath can like smite and do stuff
Delwath: I know. Wow, I rolled like three ones.
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: 7d12 is actually pretty good
DM: Yeah
Unknown: Solid roll
DM: Um,
DM: at the end of Delwath's turn it's gonna use its last legendary action to just make a pseudopod attack against Wellby with advantage
Unknown: I mean-
DM: That's a 20-something
Kenzo: ... legendary actions are good too
Delwath: I might be calling Delwath. I'm trying to get it to like attack me-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... do 300 points of damage, and then I'll turn back into Delwath-
DM: Um-
Delwath: ... with full hit points
DM: ... 4 plus 18, so 22 total damage
Delwath: That'll do it. I mean...
Unknown: Yep.
DM: So that is after Delwath's turn.
DM: Now we're back up to the start. It's, it's turn again.
Kenzo: You have a legendary?
Seeker: I actually could do a legendary now, yeah
DM: Yes, you could do a legendary as Delwath
Unknown: Slam it
Seeker: I'll do my slam again.
Seeker: [dice rolling] Oh, five and a four.
Delwath: Um, do we still have advantage?
Delwath: Yes, until Wellby's turn now
DM: Until Wellby's turn you have advantage
Delwath: That's gonna miss though. 19 misses.
DM: Yeah, 19 misses.
Kenzo: Okay. So that's just one attack.
Delwath: We only get one attack as legendary
DM: Oh, yeah
Unknown: Ah, yes.
DM: Uh, okay
Seeker: Oh, and this is weird.
Seeker: It has water form. The leviathan can enter a hostile creature's space and stop there.
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: So I could like go on top of it-
DM: Mm-hmm
Seeker: ... and I could actually kind of go as far as I want, 'cause 120-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... in the water
Kenzo: Well, let's, we're trying to snap this tendril off-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... so try to do something here to-
DM: Oh, that's a good idea. Well, the water ends about in the middle of it.
DM: It's like half into the water
Seeker: But I still have 20 feet move
Unknown: on land
DM: Yeah, so you can-
Seeker: I'll just end my move and go here
DM: Okay.
DM: So this massive leviathan crawls through the ooze-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... and then settles
DM: as a like a water, pure water sort of on top, which it writhes and struggles against.
DM: And then is going to
DM: blast-
Delwath: Wait, who's... Oh, Kenzo's next, right?
DM: It's, its turn. It's gonna blast a line of acid that hits
DM: that, that hits Seeker Leviathan and Delwath.
DM: Uh, so-
Delwath: We're immune to acid damage
Unknown: Is that Wellby? It's your...
Kenzo: Seeker Leviathan and Wellby?
DM: And Wellby, yeah. Sorry
Delwath: And it's acid damage?
DM: It is acid damage
Unknown: Okay. Ha, ha,
Unknown: ha, ha
DM: Dexterity saving throw-
Delwath: We're immune to acid damage
DM: ... for Wellby
Unknown: Oh
DM: With disadvantage 'cause you're restrained.
DM: Yeah,
DM: s- not doing... It's not great against a levi- a leviathan [laughs]
Unknown: 18
DM: Uh, that fails
Delwath: Uh, Bardic.
Wellby: There you go. [dice rolling] Uh,
Unknown: 26
DM: 26 succeeds
Unknown: There we go
DM: So you take-
Delwath: Wow, the turn hesitant succeeds on 26
Delwath: [laughs] You take no damage
Unknown: Wow
DM: That's the end of its turn?
DM: No, that's just the first thing it did this turn
Unknown: Oh, right, okay
DM: It's gonna make two attacks now
Delwath: All right, can I just... The initiative order is-
DM: Okay, Kenzo-
Unknown: Kenzo-
DM: Wellby, Seeker, Delwath
Delwath: ... I just want to do a legendary.
Delwath: Kenzo, Wellby-
DM: You can do a legendary after its turn-
Unknown: It's, after Kenzo
DM: ... after Kenzo's turn.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Uh, so it's gonna make two...
DM: It's clearly, um, angry at
DM: Wellby,
DM: so make two-
Delwath: You're like, it's not your weekend
DM: It's gonna make two attacks against Wellby, both with advantage.
DM: One hits, the other is a 21.
DM: Does 21 hit?
Wellby: It does not
Kenzo: What the fuck, man? We've got these two huge ass leviathans.
Kenzo: I'm resistant to everything. Why are the things going after you, dude?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Possibly because we're all resistant to its damage
Kenzo: No, but it's an ooze. How does it know?
Unknown: I know. It shouldn't. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Uh, sorry, that's 15 plus
DM: 9-
Unknown: Awesome
DM: ... so 24 for the first hit-
Unknown: That's not bad
DM: ... and then 15 plus- ...
DM: nine I rolled the exact same thing twice.
DM: Um, I mean, you might stop to think for like a second about why it might be a gecko against Wellby.
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause he's the tongue of the pseudopod.
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Um-
Wellby: All right, I just lost half my hit points-
DM: That ends its turn
Wellby: ... in the course of one round.
Delwath: Okay. Legendary action, move 140 feet to join my friend.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
DM: Uh, I don't know what it's gonna do about this.
Delwath: Leviathan friends
Delwath: be together.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Playful tail.
Delwath: Yeah, you get like a fri- like, Delwath is radiating a sense of real anger about this thing 'cause, like, Delwath is identifying as the Leviathan protector of nature here.
Delwath: Um, coming out of the water, this is an intrusion of the water.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: We have to destroy it.
Delwath: And he's like, "This is my buddy, Smart Leviathan, who knows what to do, so I'm just gonna follow him."
DM: [laughs] Right.
Seeker: [laughs] I'm the l- I'm the nerd Leviathan.
DM: Exactly.
Unknown: It's really obvious which one I am.
Delwath: Well, that was a legendary action.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: All right, uh, is Seeker doing any legendary actions?
Seeker: I think I burned mine all since my last turn, yeah.
DM: Oh, okay.
Wellby: Yeah, you used all your
DM: So you need to wait till your turn.
Wellby: You used your...
DM: Okay, so now it's Kenzo's turn.
Kenzo: All right, Kenzo will, uh, move.
Kenzo: Uh, I, I've got 70 move, so I can easily get over here 'cause I'm gonna get into the action over on this side.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And then, yeah, I'm, I'm gonna try to, uh, break, snap the tendril.
Kenzo: And now I get, uh, two staff attacks.
Kenzo: Is this advantage now or no? Just normal attacks?
DM: Until Wellby's turn-
Unknown: Let me check
DM: ... advantage... till Wellby's turn, so advantage
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Okay, great. So this is my first staff attack.
Kenzo: Uh, that hits and that, the...
Kenzo: well, actually, let me, let me roll the two staff attacks.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Uh, okay, definitely they both hit and then I do...
Unknown: 3d 12 plus...
DM: Plus 12
Kenzo: ... d t- no, plus 2d6.
DM: Oh, the d6.
DM: No, the d6 is only for your punches, not your staff.
Kenzo: No, no, no, it's for any melee attacks.
DM: Oh, okay.
Kenzo: Yeah. Uh, so it's this plus
Unknown: 16,
Delwath: right? Or 18.
DM: 18.
Kenzo: Hold on, that's not your spell check, sorry.
DM: It's some... it's 19, I think.
DM: No, it has to be an even number.
Kenzo: Okay. Yeah, 18, plus 18.
Delwath: That was 'cause I thought last turn was 18.
DM: 18.
Kenzo: These are just the staff attacks.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: So this...
Unknown: ooh, this is good.
Unknown: That's a good roll [laughs].
Kenzo: Oh, it's very good. Uh, 22, 32, 37, plus 18 is 47, 55.
DM: So as Kenzo-
Unknown: 55
DM: ... swings down with the staff like three, twice, like hammering on the pseudopod, like part of its,
DM: part of its-
Wellby: Does it break off a piece of this?
DM: No, no. Part of its body-
Unknown: Oh, no
Delwath: ... flows out from here-
Delwath: What? It's reinforcing
DM: ... and reinforces.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Yeah, that's a cool mechanic.
Seeker: That's awesome. It's like rebuilding itself.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
Delwath: It can flow hit points from itself to the pseudopod.
Unknown: Oh, boy. Okay.
Delwath: This thing probably has 1,000 hit points.
Kenzo: Oh, boy. Fun, fun, fun. All right, so I'm gonna do-
Delwath: Hold on, how much damage did you do?
Unknown: 55.
Kenzo: Um, now I'm gonna do my three punch attacks.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, uh, first attack, that definitely hits.
Kenzo: Second attack, ooh, natural 20.
DM: Nat 20.
Kenzo: And then third attack,
Unknown: that still hits.
Unknown: 20, 21, 21.
DM: 21 hits, yep.
Kenzo: Yeah, so that, that still hits. All right. So now I do...
Unknown: what do I do?
Unknown: You do
Unknown: 4-
DM: The natural-
Unknown: ...
Delwath: 42 plus...
Unknown: 46.
DM: 'Cause they all hit.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: 4d 12 plus 4d 6 plus-
DM: So you get to do an extra d12 and an extra d6
Delwath: ... um, and you do plus 7 instead of plus 9, right?
Unknown: Correct.
Delwath: So plus 21.
Unknown: 7, times 2, plus 21.
Delwath: So 4d 12 plus 4d 6 plus 21.
DM: Holy shit.
Kenzo: Doing a lot of damage now.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Double 20s is pretty sweet.
Wellby: 46.
Delwath: Nah, you need one more d12.
Unknown: Here.
Kenzo: 46 plus 4d 12 plus what?
Unknown: 21.
Kenzo: Plus 21.
Unknown: Ooh.
Seeker: Yeah, plus 21. Cool.
Delwath: Man, you're doing good on the damage rolls today.
Kenzo: I'm getting all the 20s.
Unknown: 15, 20,
Unknown: uh, 30, 40.
Unknown: 40.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
DM: And move some stone back.
Kenzo: 40, uh, what the fuck is this?
DM: Harnessing-
Unknown: Plus, uh, uh, 6 plus-
DM: 54
Unknown: ... 54 plus-
Delwath: Plus 21. 60,
Unknown: 75.
DM: Wow.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Kenzo: Holy shit, that's the most damage I've ever done in a turn.
DM: So a-
Unknown: Damn
DM: ... sorry. Okay, after Kenzo [laughs]...
Unknown: Holy shit
DM: ...
DM: uh-
Kenzo: Advantage Kenzo at 20 level up is pretty nasty.
DM: So after Kenzo punches, a bunch of the stone
DM: in its body
DM: goes back and you find...
DM: and it's forming a s- like a stone barrier along this pseudopod.
Delwath: I'm gonna use a legendary action to...
Delwath: another fist of water appears and slams into it, like right here.
Unknown: [dice rolling] 13, that'll hit.
Unknown: 25.
DM: Okay. Is this bludgeoning damage?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, is it resistant to bludgeoning damage now?
Seeker: Is this gonna be where the more damage we do to this thing, the stronger it gets?
Unknown: I don't think so.
Unknown: 13.
DM: Um, the fist of water-
Unknown: I thought we gave it a way to like, you know
DM: ... hits into the stone and the energy is partially dissipated
DM: along the line of the pseudopod.
Unknown: Heal damage or something.
DM: Sorry, how much was that?
Unknown: 13.
DM: So like a half.
Wellby: Like a desecrate spell or something like that.
Unknown: Okay, 6. [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Guys, I did 120 damage on like a regular attack.
Delwath: Ha. That, uh, if it gains resistance to bludgeoning damage, that it's now like gonna be hard for us to actually hurt it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Is it resistant to bludgeoning?
DM: It's reinforced the pseudopod with-
Unknown: It's reinforced
DM: ... see all the stone?
Delwath: But you, you also do... oh, no, you do-
Wellby: Why don't we just go further down
Unknown: ... do you do force damage or bludgeoning damage?
Wellby: I mean, if the pseudopod goes all the way back to the next door, we just go down another 50 feet.
Delwath: It's probably reinforcing the whole...
DM: Uh, yeah, the stone is filling out as far as you can see.
DM: But it's only 30 feet.
Unknown: Sure.
DM: Um, sorry, I'm losing track.
DM: That was...
DM: uh, it wants to do a legendary action.
DM: Wait, did you already do a legendary action?
Delwath: That damage was just my legendary action.
DM: Okay, well, that's fine. It's gonna do a legendary now before Seeker does a legendary action.
DM: Um-
Delwath: [laughs] This is a little ridiculous.
DM: It is. Uh, and- Man, immune to acid is really tough for it to do much against.
Unknown: That's why the devil-
DM: Oh, wait, are you immune to poison?
Unknown: No.
DM: Oh, wait, you are immune to poison.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: God damn it. Okay.
Delwath: I can't roll it hard enough.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: Winning the game
Delwath: ... like, there is 25% of us.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But this is really good for Seeker, 'cause you can just cast your spells.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But actually,
Delwath: my attacks are getting less and less effective, 'cause it's all blun- it's all damage it's also resistant to.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: So we're like two giants trading ineffective hits against each other.
Kenzo: Yeah. Which is n- I mean, not bad.
Unknown: I mean, I'm doing okay.
Delwath: If I could get it to attack me, that would be good.
Unknown: That would be great.
DM: [sighs] Kenzo is the l- Kenzo just did a ton of damage along this pseudopod.
DM: So Kenzo, make a dexterity saving throw,
DM: as more of this acid net flies out towards you.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
DM: You-
Kenzo: Uh, I, I spent a ki earlier
DM: ... that fails. Okay.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh my gosh.
DM: [coughs] So you are now...
DM: You take-
Unknown: 16.
DM: Yeah, that fails.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You take, um,
DM: 44 reduced by...
DM: Oh, double reduced, because-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you're-
Kenzo: Both immune and resistant
DM: ... right. So you take-
Unknown: 11
DM: ... 11 points of
DM: damage, but you are now also restrained.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: So annoying.
DM: B- same as Wellby. So speed is zero, attacks against you have advantage.
DM: Um, your attacks have disadvantage.
DM: At the end of your turn, you can make another save to escape.
Kenzo: Dude, how did I fail two fucking dex saves?
DM: That's... It's legendary.
Unknown: Are you fucking serious?
DM: Okay. Wellby's turn. Uh, unless Seeker wants to do...
DM: Oh, no, Seeker's out of legendaries till his turn.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: So Wellby's up.
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: So your attacks have disadvantage until, uh...
DM: Oh, well, advantage.
Unknown: Advantage.
DM: So it cancels out, so straight one.
Wellby: Sure. Well, do I still get sneak attack because there's an ally within 5?
DM: Yes. Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Are you aiming for the main body or the tail?
Wellby: Uh, tail is not yet resistant to piercing damage.
DM: No.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You think it's only resistant to bludgeoning.
DM: It probably can't be resistant to multiple things at once.
Wellby: Uh, is it the same day as it was yesterday, or is this...
Wellby: Do we long... We long rested.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: I'll use the clockwork amulet to roll a 24.
DM: That hits.
Wellby: And I'll get some more dice.
Delwath: Um, is Delwath next?
Unknown: No, Seeker's next.
DM: Seeker's next, then Delwath.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Five, uh,
Wellby: 22, 25, 30-
DM: Sorry, you are a- you are shooting at the t- at the pseudopod
Wellby: ... 35. Yep. Uh, 39 plus 8 is 47.
DM: Nice.
Wellby: Can I get more bardic inspiration?
Wellby: Is that a... That's not a thing you can do in this form?
DM: Not as a leviathan, you can't.
DM: Uh-
Wellby: Uh, and then save to escape grapple?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Great.
DM: Dex save to escape the restraints.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: You can only do it at the end of the turn.
DM: End of your turn. Yeah.
Unknown: Dex save?
DM: Dex save.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Seeker, you're up. Restr- yeah, that's where the restraints...
Unknown: No, it is not. Come on.
DM: Uh-
Seeker: I'm thinking about just psychic disruption again.
Wellby: 15 probably doesn't do it.
DM: Nope.
Wellby: Should I use my heroic?
Kenzo: Probably, man. You want to get the fuck out of this thing.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. 'Cause it can keep doing new things.
Kenzo: D- this is like one of those, like, I feel like saves are just important to spend, you know, if you can get out of them.
Unknown: Uh, 20?
DM: Nope.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: Oh, no. [laughs]
DM: Hey, their DC is 24.
DM: Why should its be any le- worse?
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: That's rough.
Wellby: Uh, uh, because I rolled poorly, is the answer.
DM: Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Damn.
Unknown: It is very-
DM: Um, but as your arrow strikes, um, the...
DM: Well, actually, wait.
DM: Uh, that was at the end of your turn, so now it's gonna use its legendary.
DM: Um-
Wellby: Will you release me from the restraints?
DM: Nope. To attack you.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Y- you're noticing a pattern-
Unknown: Oh, oh
DM: ... it basically is just attacking whoever was the last one to do damage to its tail.
Wellby: Hold up. I'm gonna use my bonus action to get my second wind.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: And regain three hit points.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: That's still more than zero hit points.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: So it has advantage on you.
DM: Um,
DM: two natural ones.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: So with your second wind-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... you dodge out of the way.
DM: That's its legendary. Anybody else want to do legendaries?
Unknown: I'm out.
Unknown: Same.
DM: Okay. So-
Unknown: It was only my turn
DM: ... so Seeker's up.
Seeker: I will try again another psychic disruption.
Seeker: This time at sixth level.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: with, uh, DC 19 save.
DM: Uh, okay.
DM: Whoops.
DM: Um,
DM: it's gonna burn a legendary resistance.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And it hardens slightly, reducing its speed
DM: as it uses its legendary resistance, which seems like it may have no effect because everybody's crowded around it.
DM: Um-
Seeker: So I'll roll the 9d6 and take half?
DM: Uh, yep.
Unknown: So that's-
DM: That's its first legendary that it's burned
Seeker: ... 23 over two is
Unknown: 11.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay. And that's on the...
DM: That was your turn.
Seeker: Um, I c- I guess I could also move if I wanted to, but-
DM: I'm not sure the point.
Unknown: Yeah. Right.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Can you cast spells?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Seeker can cast spells as a leviathan.
DM: Delwath cannot.
Delwath: Delwath can't, because she
DM: Um,
DM: okay. Now it's gonna use, uh...
DM: It used, it's used two legendaries.
DM: It's actually gonna use its last legendary-
Unknown: To attack Seeker.
DM: No, 'cause it doesn't really recognize that spells are attacks.
Unknown: No.
DM: It can't tell where the spell comes from.
Unknown: Is it gonna go for Wellby again?
DM: Yeah, 'cause Wellby's the last one that damaged it.
Unknown: Damn it.
Wellby: Yeah, but I got that big three.
Unknown: Yeah, you do get-
DM: Three?
Seeker: ... that, that, that big three. What's your total, AJ?
Wellby: 86 right now.
Unknown: I th-
DM: Well, that was a one.
DM: [dice clatter] Uh, that was a 20, a 15, so it's...
DM: Sorry, an 8 plus 15 is 23.
Unknown: That's it.
DM: Okay, so that's gonna do-
Unknown: Hit there
DM: ... 20 bludgeoning plus five acid, so 25 total.
Unknown: Whoa.
Wellby: Awesome. Yep. Good.
DM: That's, its legendary Seeker turn is over.
DM: Delwath is up.
Seeker: Okay. Oh, I can do my legendary after.
DM: After, after Delwath.
Delwath: Delwath is gonna, like-
DM: You can't do legends after your own turn after, only after somebody else's turn.
Seeker: But wasn't it just its turn?
DM: No, no.
DM: It was, it was its legendary.
DM: You were its legendary. [laughs]
Unknown: Oh. [laughs]
Unknown: You were its legendary.
Unknown: Thank you. Great.
DM: You are its legendary. [laughs]
Delwath: Right. Delwath will, like-
Unknown: So it's just legendary attacks all the way
Delwath: ... will, like, roar at it in anger-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... like, like, you know, "You're a terrible thing," like, and form a sort of whirlwind of, um, of water that swirls around and just slams into it twice.
DM: The tail or the main body?
Delwath: The tail.
DM: Okay.
DM: But misses the first time.
DM: That misses. [dice clatter]
Delwath: Uh, does 21 hit?
DM: 21 hits, yep.
Delwath: Hits the second time.
Delwath: Uh, so hits with the tail, which is less good, but
Delwath: oh my God.
DM: [scoffs]
Delwath: For, for 11 points of bludgeoning damage.
Seeker: We're doing peanuts for damage right now.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: We need Kenzo to hit again.
Unknown: [laughs] Or 10 times that.
DM: Um, 11. Okay, so-
Unknown: Six, five.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Six. I forget if you round up or down.
DM: You round down.
Kenzo: I'm doing a lot of damage.
DM: Um, the... Even so, with that hit, even though it was weak, you can see cracks starting to form in the tail.
Seeker: All right.
DM: Uh, that's gonna be its turn.
DM: It now turns in anger at Delwath.
Unknown: Yay.
Unknown: Oh, nice.
Unknown: Finally.
DM: That was the goal.
Unknown: Finally, geez.
DM: And it's going to make, uh,
DM: three pseudo-pod attacks.
Unknown: Yep. [dice clatter] Let's go.
DM: Uh, a one.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: The first one misses as it's-
Unknown: It's only one
DM: ... distracted by-
Unknown: I think we're almost-
DM: The second one is a 30-something.
Delwath: Yeah, AC's only 17.
DM: And the third is a 21.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So two hit.
DM: You're immune to acid?
Delwath: Yep, immune to acid, immune to poison, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing and slashing.
DM: Uh, okay. So you take 20,
DM: 35 reduced by half.
Delwath: That's two hits.
DM: That's two hits, yeah.
Unknown: And do I have to make con saves?
DM: Yep.
Delwath: Yeah, I have to make...
Delwath: So 35 reduced to
Unknown: 12.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Sorry, that was, that's,
Delwath: that was the fir- that was the first hit, 35.
Delwath: The first hit was 35.
DM: 35 reduced by two.
Unknown: Okay. So what is that?
Unknown: 15-
Seeker: Also, we should be adding the temporary hit points of 328.
DM: Um, the second hit is 27.
DM: [dice clatter]
Delwath: 15, that's okay.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: And the second hit is 27-
DM: 27, so it's 13
Unknown: ... so 13.
Seeker: So I have over 500 total now.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. [dice clatter] [laughs]
Unknown: That's okay.
DM: That's okay.
Kenzo: It's just, like, massive, like, hit point...
DM: Um, and then it is going to, uh,
DM: shoot another
DM: w- a line of acid can actually hit all four of you right now.
DM: So a line of acid is gonna erupt from right here and just fly out, like [gurgling] in a straight line hitting all four of you.
DM: Everybody has to make a dex saving throw, Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
DM: Wait, did you s- you didn't succeed, did you?
Unknown: No, I did not.
DM: Okay, so Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
Delwath: Do I have to... Is this... Does that erase it?
DM: No. It's also immune to restraint.
Kenzo: I'm also immune to restraint.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: 19?
DM: What?
DM: 19 fails.
Unknown: 18.
DM: Fails.
Unknown: Fails.
Delwath: Is that the end of its turn?
DM: That's the end of its turn.
Unknown: Wait, do I, do I have to roll? No.
DM: No, 'cause it's acid damage.
DM: [laughs] You're immune to acid damage.
Unknown: Acid and restraint. You're immune to acid and restraint.
DM: So you two both take 33 points of acid damage.
Kenzo: Yeah, but also I'm resistant to it.
DM: Oh, you take half of that.
DM: So you take 16 points of acid damage.
Delwath: I will punch it again as a legendary.
Wellby: Uh, 33 is the half already?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Well, I'm also gonna do my legendary.
DM: Okay, so that's the end of the...
Unknown: Um, so-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... 23 hits, right?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I'm at 28 hit points.
Delwath: I'm trying here.
Delwath: Uh, 23 hits?
DM: 23 hits, yep.
Unknown: 2D12. [dice clatter] That's better.
Delwath: 15, uh, plus 8, so 23.
Unknown: And then-
DM: Okay
Seeker: ... in my slam attack.
Unknown: [dice clatter] What is this?
Unknown: 20.
DM: 20.
Unknown: Misses.
DM: Uh, 20 mi- t- uh, 20 misses.
DM: No, 20 just hits.
Unknown: Okay. I thought it was a miss.
DM: Uh, 20 hits. You, nobody's rolled a 20 yet.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You've only rolled 19s or 12s.
Delwath: 2D12 plus 8, bludgeoning.
Delwath: Uh, 13 plus 8, 21.
DM: So 21, and what was yours?
DM: I didn't write it down. I'm sorry.
Unknown: It was also 21.
DM: Okay. So,
DM: um, more cracks begin to run along this, this tendril.
DM: [dice clatter]
Delwath: Wait, uh, y- you know, you should bonus action Healing Word on your next turn.
Unknown: That would be great.
DM: So Kenzo's up.
Delwath: You only got it on your last turn.
Delwath: Oh, no, you can't cast two level spells.
Kenzo: What's my deal again now? 'Cause I'm restrained.
DM: So disadvantage on all attacks.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: Your move is zero.
Kenzo: That's fine. And then I can try to-
DM: At the end of your turn, you get another dex save to escape.
Seeker: That would be great. Hang on. All right.
DM: And remember, it attacks whoever attacked it last.
Kenzo: That's fine. I want it to attack me.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: All right. Uh, so just initiative-
Delwath: Wait, where is it? I-
DM: Losing track of the initiative order
DM: Kenzo, Wellby, Seeker, Delwath, then it.
Unknown: It's first.
Kenzo: Oh man, I rolled a 20 and a 2, so that misses, right?
DM: That misses, yeah.
Kenzo: 17 misses. [dice clatter] Fuck, I rolled a 1.
DM: Misses.
Unknown: Damn it.
DM: Your... As you try and get it with your staff, the, like, acid net around you is holding you back.
Kenzo: First one, I'm strike.
Unknown: Uh-
Delwath: It's at 20 AC. You don't have a plus 16, do you?
Unknown: I do not.
DM: Nope, that misses.
Kenzo: Disadvantage sucks.
DM: It does.
Unknown: Man.
Unknown: All right, that hits.
DM: That hits.
Unknown: All right.
DM: You're right, you gotta beat these saves.
Kenzo: Hold on, that... Hold on. And then the last one, um, [dice clatter] that also hits.
Kenzo: All right, so two hit.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So I do-
DM: So 2D12 plus 2D6.
Unknown: No, uh, 3D12. [dice clatter]
DM: No, the, you have-
Kenzo: I, I get to spend an extra D12 on the-
DM: He, he gets an extra D12-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... on the first attack that hits.
Kenzo: Right. So 3D12, 2D6 plus 10.
DM: And this is force damage?
Unknown: Force damage, yeah.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: I can, I can make it force damage.
DM: And there's no way it can be resistant to force damage.
Kenzo: Oh, pl- uh, plus 14.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Plus 14.
Unknown: [dice clatter] Oh, that's good.
Kenzo: 22, 25,
Kenzo: 29 plus 14.
DM: Kenzo's really, like...
DM: How much?
Delwath: Uh, 29 plus 14.
Unknown: 43.
DM: And that's all force?
Kenzo: Yep, all force. Yeah.
Kenzo: That's only with two hits.
DM: Like, four big cracks spread along
DM: this
DM: tendril here.
DM: It's not, it's not quite, you know,
DM: broken but...
DM: It's still resistant to bludgeoning.
DM: [dice clatter]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That, uh... So make your dex save to try and break free.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Nope.
Unknown: Static keep.
Unknown: Reroll.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Thank you. That's gotta, that's gotta work.
Unknown: 25.
DM: That works. [dice clatter] It is still gonna attack you though, without advantage this time, with its legendary at the end of your turn.
DM: That, [sighs] that's a one.
Delwath: The big giant monsters are really rolling poorly.
DM: I know. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Ken's... Yes.
Unknown: All of us.
Unknown: All of us, yeah.
DM: So it is Wellby's turn.
Unknown: [sighs]
DM: Or unless anybody wants legendaries.
Delwath: I used them up. Well, I can move.
Unknown: I-
Unknown: I'm, I'm done.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: 'Cause the slam is two legendaries.
DM: I see.
Delwath: So we can only do one slam.
DM: One slam per.
Delwath: And there's not really a point in moving.
DM: Right.
Wellby: I can probably survive one more hit.
Wellby: Uh, I will shoot its-
DM: Have you been rolling to see if your tidal wave recharges on your turns?
Unknown: Oh, I've forgotten. I don't...
Unknown: Actually,
Unknown: no.
Delwath: Roll a D6 to see if your tidal wave...
Unknown: Well, you haven't used it yet.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Is this one of three of these we have to beat, or is this the one we have to beat?
Unknown: We don't know.
Kenzo: I think this is one of three. Well, for sure we're gonna have to fight something in the well.
Kenzo: This is, this is... We may be able to avoid the other one, but...
Unknown: This is the small one.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Uh, okay. Well, I will shoot it then.
Wellby: Um, that's a
Wellby: 23 or something like that.
DM: Yes. Yeah, it is a 20, I see.
Unknown: 4,
Unknown: 8,
Unknown: 9.
Delwath: It's, it's next, right?
Unknown: Uh...
DM: No. Seeker and Delwath are next.
Unknown: Oh, we're next.
DM: It's Wellby's turn. It is very difficult to keep track of the turn order-
Unknown: I know
Wellby: ... with this many [laughs] legendary actions.
Wellby: 10, 15, 22, 31 damage and then I will bonus action drink my last potion of
Wellby: s- a small amount of healing. A greater healing.
Unknown: That's some d4s.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, that ends your turn?
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Is that that... Oh, and I roll, uh...
DM: To escape.
Unknown: Nope.
DM: It's going to attack you
DM: with its legendary action.
DM: Uh, that's, uh...
DM: That hits.
Wellby: Awesome. Oops.
DM: So you take 18 bludgeoning plus 8 acid.
Delwath: Can't you uncanny dodge that?
Wellby: No, 'cause I'm restrained.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: I assume I can't uncanny dodge when I'm restrained.
DM: Uh...
Wellby: I mean, that's a thing.
DM: I think... I mean, yeah, you...
DM: There's nothing that says... You just have, you have disadvantage on dex saving throws.
Delwath: Unless uncanny dodge requires you to have speed.
DM: I don't think uncann- Does uncanny dodge say you can't use it if your speed is zero?
DM: I know that Ken's, the, the dodge action is you can't use it if your speed is zero.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Dude, Kenzo's really unkillable.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I also have, like, my, my, my, uh-
DM: Okay. So yeah, you can use that.
Wellby: All right. So that's n- uh, what is the total damage?
DM: The... It was 18 and 6, so 20...
Unknown: 24.
Unknown: So 12.
DM: 24, so 12. [pen clatter] Uh, that's its le- [laughs] legendary action.
DM: You're still restrained.
DM: You should actually be rolling all these...
DM: I forgot 'cause you're restrained, you have disadvantage on dex, so you should be rolling the saves to escape with disadvantage.
Unknown: Oh, that's rough.
Unknown: Really?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Did I have disadvantage to escape?
DM: It's pretty nasty to be restrained because...
DM: I mean, you might have ways to get out of...
DM: I mean,
DM: Delwath has, like, 10 ways to get out of restraints.
Wellby: Yeah, also the magic waist.
Delwath: But also is currently, uh, in water elemental form.
DM: [laughs] In two restraints.
Unknown: And immune to restraint.
Wellby: Uh, it doesn't really matter 'cause I've failed them all.
DM: Yeah, exactly. It's Seeker's turn.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: You might just Leviathan smash it and heal Wellby.
Unknown: Oh, that's a good idea.
DM: Of course.
Kenzo: That very first save. [laughs]
DM: As Kong said... [laughs]
Unknown: It's true.
Seeker: You're like, "Ah, just, just see what happens."
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I assumed it was just damage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Um, I cast a healing word at
Seeker: fifth level.
Unknown: So that's 1d-
Kenzo: It's so crazy how, like, like, saving throws are just, like, the most important thing actually.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: 10d4 plus 5.
Delwath: Just roll that on there.
Unknown: Um...
Kenzo: 10d4 plus 5.
Kenzo: Oh, that's a lot of d4s.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Uh, it's 29.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Awesome.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: That more than doubles my hit points.
Unknown: Amazing.
Unknown: And then, uh-
Delwath: I mean, you can take your full attacks.
Unknown: You can attack twice
Seeker: ... so, like, the multi attack is a slam and a tail.
Delwath: A slam and a tail, yeah.
Seeker: Yeah, they're both plus 14 to hit.
Delwath: Both plus 14. One gets slightly discounted.
DM: Uh, main body or tail? The tail has, like, four large cracks in it.
Unknown: Tail.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Oh, nice.
DM: Go ahead.
Unknown: 16 and an 18.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So 2d10-
Unknown: 32 to 33
Delwath: ... 2d10 plus 2d12.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: Plus 16.
DM: Nice. Love this.
Seeker: Now we're talk- now we're talking, Levi.
DM: Love this.
Delwath: Oh, wow. Not a good roll.
Unknown: Oh, I got-
Unknown: Kinda good, but...
Seeker: ... 14 plus 7 is 21 plus...
Delwath: Plus 16.
Unknown: Is 37.
Unknown: 37.
Unknown: Nice. Nice roll.
Delwath: 37 bludgeoning from two big fists.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: A fist and a tail.
Delwath: A fist and a tail.
Delwath: Oh, Delwath's tidal breath recharges
DM: Uh [laughs]
Unknown: I'm just gonna sit tight.
DM: Well [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, two more big cracks appear, and it
DM: f- roars up and launches a massive punch at Seeker.
Unknown: Yay.
DM: That's a 19, so that...
DM: Uh, sorry, a 19 on the die, so that hits.
Delwath: Yeah, it's a 14. These guys don't have great AC.
DM: Um, and-
Unknown: 14 AC, yeah
DM: ... you take 14 points of bludgeoning and zero points of acid from the pseudopod.
Unknown: You do.
Delwath: So with resistance to bludgeoning, is 14 already halved or no?
DM: No.
Unknown: So seven.
DM: So
DM: seven.
Seeker: Ah. So I take seven off of my 328.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah. So you, but you do have to make a con save.
Unknown: [coughs] Oh, shit, yeah.
Delwath: That's okay. You only have to roll a...
DM: You actually-
Delwath: Actually, you can't fail
DM: ... do they have, where they have plus?
Unknown: 10.
DM: So you can't fail. You don't have to make a con save.
Unknown: Wait, why did I-
DM: 'Cause if you roll a one, it's 11, and you only have to beat a 10.
Seeker: Because of the constitution of a leviathan.
Delwath: The con is plus 10 of the leviathan. It has to do-
Unknown: That seems critical [laughs].
Delwath: It has to do more-
DM: That's very true
Delwath: ... oh, that's a good point. It has to do more than 22 damage for you to have to roll a con save.
DM: 20, which is tough when you're resistant.
Delwath: With resistance.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Yeah. Okay, uh.
Unknown: That's a good combo.
DM: That was a legendary, so Delwath is up.
Delwath: Okay, Delwath's turn. I'm gonna, I'm gonna tidal wave again.
Unknown: Now-
Unknown: Why are you tidal waving?
Unknown: Well-
DM: Spells are better.
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: Delwath can't cast spells.
Unknown: I can cast spells.
Unknown: Got it, got it.
Seeker: And it's, and it's a strength save, and it's gonna hit everybody.
DM: It's very good at strength saves.
Delwath: No, I just make it right he- the- they're still flying, right?
Kenzo: I don't know if we're still flying.
Unknown: Well, I'll make the-
DM: You made the...
Delwath: I'll make the tidal wave appear here and go that way.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: There we go. That's great.
DM: That you can do.
Unknown: Great.
Seeker: Oh, right. I think I misread it at first.
Seeker: You can make it small if you want to.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So it's not
DM: Right.
Unknown: Tidal wave.
DM: So that's a strength save [laughs].
Delwath: Yeah, DC 24 strength save.
Delwath: I mean, DC 24 is a little bit tough, even if it's a plus 10.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh, yeah, it rolled a two.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So that's only a 16.
Kenzo: I'm still not getting super, super psyched about the, uh, because of his face and that, so that's not great.
Unknown: That's fair. I mean, it's...
DM: Yeah. So 7d12.
Seeker: It popped his collar and it's...
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] I didn't do that for this, this character.
DM: That's five as well.
Kenzo: When he's attacking, he switches his face and it pops his collar.
DM: 10, 22, 32-
Unknown: He's angry
DM: ...
DM: 38 plus
Delwath: eight is, uh, 46.
DM: Oh, wait, sorry. It's gonna use a legendary resistance.
DM: So half of 46.
DM: Ugh.
Unknown: Uh...
Wellby: What's the pseudopod situation?
Delwath: Does it like wash away in the tidal wave?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Great.
DM: And the ooze
DM: begins to bubble
DM: and split apart. [slimy sounds]
Kenzo: I like the sound effects.
DM: As
DM: with that blast,
DM: I made it too strong.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It falls to pieces and begins to drain away, crystallizing and hardening as you hit it.
Unknown: Oh, nice.
Unknown: Awesome.
DM: And there is a rumbling sound.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: The rumbling
Unknown: ... no rumbling.
DM: And the earth begins to shake.
Unknown: What?
Seeker: And we, we, uh-
DM: And what do you do?
Wellby: We go take a long rest.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: The leviathan-
Wellby: Well, uh, can I get out of the...
Wellby: I assume the-
DM: You're not restrained anymore. Yeah, it, uh...
Wellby: Oh.
DM: Um, actual- wow, [laughs] it actually hardens into crystal.
Kenzo: Kenzo goes over and breaks out-
Unknown: Well, well, well
Kenzo: ... breaks out the, the-
DM: Uh, yeah, but that's...
DM: Let me keep track of how long these things take you.
Delwath: Um-
DM: So anybody can free either one of them with a, with automatically with a help action, or you can break out as an action.
Delwath: Well, can I use a wedger action to break them out?
DM: Mm-hmm. Sure, you can wash it away.
Delwath: I have, I have a 27 strength.
DM: Yes. Yes, yes, yes.
Delwath: A big, the, the, the w- river comes and swooshes across you.
DM: Swooshes it away.
Delwath: Dissolving the acid with it.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Ah. The crystal, taking the crystal.
Unknown: Refreshing.
Seeker: With a swish of your giant flipper.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Right.
Wellby: Could you have done that when it was acid?
DM: No.
Wellby: That would've been nice.
DM: There, this is just a, this is just a color flare.
Wellby: All right.
DM: There's no mechanism for somebody to help you break out of-
Wellby: Got it
DM: ... restraint in this case.
DM: Sometimes there are-
Wellby: Right
DM: ... but this particular one, no.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: So, um, you can, you can hear in the distance, like a faint cracking, crumbling sound, like stones and earth falling.
Delwath: Go towards it.
Delwath: I don't know, I'm not very smart.
Unknown: Uh...
Kenzo: How long does the leviathan last?
Unknown: It's an hour.
Unknown: Little bit of healing.
Delwath: No, but, but-
Unknown: Little bit of healing
Delwath: ... Delwath's going towards it [laughs].
Unknown: Healing?
Delwath: I guess I'll wait if every, if nobody is following.
Unknown: That would be-
Wellby: Healing, you don't have magic.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: More healing?
Seeker: I can cast another healing spell on you, yes.
Delwath: Uh, you used your ninth level slot.
Delwath: This is where, uh, power heal would sort of be helpful.
Seeker: Yeah, but I, I don't have it.
Delwath: But you're a leviathan.
Kenzo: Wish I could give you some, uh,
Kenzo: some healing stuff.
Wellby: Thanks. Thanks, Kenzo.
Kenzo: I gave, I gave you my temper potion.
Wellby: Oh, you did. You did.
Seeker: I c- I could do another fifth level healing word.
Delwath: Do you have, you don't have a Q, you don't have any QRS, do you?
Wellby: I'm gaining a new appreciation for Kenzo's role as the person who just soaks up damage.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, right?
Wellby: Very good.
Kenzo: I mean, dude, I'm so good at it now too, 'cause I have, I have the, the, that boon of healing thing I got.
Kenzo: I have 10, I have 10 hit dice I can use as a bonus action.
Wellby: Wow.
Kenzo: 10, 10d10. I have a pool of 10d10s I can just roll whenever I want to gain more hit points.
Wellby: I have one more 10d10. It's like a win.
Delwath: Um, I'm wondering if I should turn back into Delwath.
Unknown: Eh.
Delwath: Eh. We'll see. I won't do it for now.
Unknown: The next thing is the-
Seeker: All right, I'm gonna do the healing word, right?
Unknown: We still got an hour.
Wellby: I've used my healing word.
Kenzo: 'Cause I... The ooze is still gonna be the same thing.
Unknown: It's gonna be 10d4 plus something.
Kenzo: So this has been very useful.
Unknown: 10d4 plus five.
Kenzo: Just from, uh, yeah,
Unknown: you not-
Unknown: Here.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 32.
Unknown: Yeah, that's, that is something.
Kenzo: Being, like, essentially immune to it.
DM: Cracked.
Kenzo: It's very useful Fuck.
Unknown: Uh,
Kenzo: well, 'cause the river connects into the cistern, right?
Kenzo: It like flows in there somehow.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Can we follow the tendril?
DM: Well, you washed it away. It's-
Unknown: Well, I know, but the tendril-
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. It's crystal-
Kenzo: ... it's reaching in this, you know, it's crystallized.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: Let's, let's follow the crystal tendril.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: See where it leads.
Seeker: Are, are we still... Are we going into the ash storm?
DM: Yeah. You're, you're in the ash st- You're...
DM: Right now, you're in the ash storm. Your visibility is only 30 feet.
Kenzo: But everybody's immune to all the stuff.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: You're-
Seeker: As long as we s- We have to stay leviathan.
DM: No, no. Heroes' Feast makes you immune to poison.
Unknown: Heroes' Feast.
Seeker: Oh, Heroes' Feast makes you immune to poison.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Let's, uh, let's follow the river.
Kenzo: Let's stay in the river. Let's... 'Cause while you guys are still leviathans, let's, let's, let's flow, let's flow with the, with the-
Delwath: Is there like another connection from the river that this was feeding through?
Unknown: Into the cistern.
Delwath: Into the cistern?
DM: Uh, wait, hold on.
DM: What do you mean?
DM: Like-
Kenzo: What are we leaving at, 4:30?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Where...
Delwath: So along the river, was there...
Delwath: We're wondering where the cistern f- was fed from the river.
Delwath: Like, is there a spot on the river where the cistern would have been fed?
DM: Uh,
DM: at the moment, n- I mean, anything that w- did used to connect them has collapsed.
Delwath: But is there like a... So there's not really a,
Delwath: there's not really a spot. So to follow the tendril would be over land, follow the tendril close to the-
DM: It's over land, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: We're literally going to the well.
DM: That's the direction it's heading, yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just fucking go to the well.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And that's where, that's where this has all gotta go anyways, right?
Kenzo: We gotta go down into the, into the well, down into the fucking...
Wellby: Yeah, we could conceivably, if we go to the well...
Wellby: If there's still two of these out there and one of them's in the well-
Delwath: We might have to fight two
Wellby: ... we wanna fight the other one not in the well, so that we only have to fight one in the well.
Kenzo: Good point. Good point.
Delwath: Well, can Kenzo...
Kenzo: Do his rogue action? Yeah, t- Tim, what's going on?
DM: Yeah, that's an action. Um, you have this...
DM: You've done it once before, so it takes a ki, but I think you have plenty of ki left.
Kenzo: I do. And, and next time we roll initiative-
DM: And roll initiative-
Unknown: ... you'll all get it back
DM: ... you'll get it all back. Um,
DM: so you... There never was three.
Kenzo: Yeah, but just, but just the, the concentration, is it, is it still those two?
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Is... Where, where are they basically?
DM: Uh, everything is centered on the well right now.
Kenzo: Great. Let's go to the well.
Wellby: Let's go to the well.
Unknown: Ugh.
Seeker: So it's sort of attracting.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So it's gonna be like a fucking 2,000 hit point...
Unknown: Yep. [laughs]
Wellby: Do we have any more healing potions hanging around?
Kenzo: I'll give you whatever I have. Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, I used my other-
Seeker: I have one, but it's inside my blubber.
Delwath: [laughs] I have one, but it's also...
Kenzo: It's inside my blubber.
Delwath: We're not gonna... But no, we're made of water.
DM: Your... But your items are also all made of water.
Delwath: I know. The leviathan's a water elemental.
Unknown: I didn't know that.
Unknown: Oh, I have a 4-
Delwath: That's why it can get, it, it can go through a space as small, as small as an inch
Unknown: ... I have four potions of greater healing.
Unknown: Can I use one?
Unknown: Yeah, of course.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Because it's, it's, uh, it's a sea serpent, but it's shaped of wa-
Unknown: That's, uh-
Delwath: It's actually a water elemental, the leviathan
Kenzo: ... 4d4 plus 4. 4d4 plus 4, so it's 8d4 plus 8.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: 8d4 plus 8.
Wellby: All right, 27. Good.
Wellby: That gets me back.
Kenzo: I... Do you not actually take the last two?
Kenzo: We're not gonna rest again until-
Wellby: Yeah, but what if like your, uh...
Unknown: Keep a couple for-
Unknown: Yeah, I mean...
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: For what?
DM: Oh, you can... I, I-
Delwath: Keep a couple, but maybe don't use them all.
DM: He can burn his action, roll a 1d10.
Delwath: Well, why not? I have no reason not to.
Wellby: Yeah. I keep one more just in case, like, I'm the last person surviving.
Kenzo: Dude, I'll give you, I'll give you the other two that I have and you can drink 'em la- drink 'em whenever you want.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: I'm gonna drink one now, keep one.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So you rush forward.
Unknown: Great. We're gonna
DM: Running towards the,
DM: uh, with these two water creatures following, running towards the,
DM: um,
DM: the center. You break out through the storm and you see that the center of this plaza has partially collapsed.
DM: And in the center
DM: is, like, a 400-foot-long ooze.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: Whoa.
Kenzo: Wait, th- this is not the well, this is, this is here.
DM: No, the cen- the plaza has collapsed.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: So it's a slope down.
Unknown: Into the cistern.
Unknown: Into the well.
DM: Into the cistern.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: And emerging out of it is this massive...
DM: Not sure actually that battle maps are gonna be that useful here.
Unknown: All right.
DM: This thing, this is, like-
Kenzo: I'm into the Lego right now
DM: ... 400 feet across.
Wellby: Are we in the eye of the storm right now?
DM: You've just emerged out from the eye of the storm.
DM: And it's, like, it's writhing, like, in anger.
Unknown: Hey, hey, down guard. You took my staff.
DM: [laughs] Looming, like, bits of it looming up, grabbing, um...
Wellby: Do you want to Counterbalance?
Unknown: Uh,
Seeker: I'm seeing if there's a way to add this in, in the...
Delwath: Put it at the b- You'd have to put it at the bottom.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: Oh, that's true. That's true.
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah, you could print that, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Nice. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: All right. Now we're talking.
Kenzo: Angel's got a, a new staff.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: All right, all right, all right. [laughs] Now we're, now we're getting somewhere.
DM: Okay, so.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: shit.
DM: You rush forward, you emerge out of the storm of ash, and you see this,
DM: like, collops- collapsed plaza.
DM: So it, like, slopes down.
DM: There's like a gradient slope down to the bottom.
DM: And at the... So just the, like, ring of the plaza is still stable.
DM: You still see those columns and the, and the, like, partial cover of the fallen, um,
DM: [laughs] of the fallen,
DM: uh, of the fallen market.
DM: But this, towards the river, the entire ground is collapsed and it just slopes down to the bottom of the cistern At which there's this m- like, just utterly enormous roiling
DM: mass of multicolored ooze bubbling and raging and beginning to climb out and rush forwards towards you.
Delwath: Can we... Is there like, um,
Delwath: is there still like the
Delwath: center down there somewhere thing that we saw earlier?
Delwath: Can we tell?
DM: You can't see it.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: It's probably somewhere inside the ooze.
Delwath: So we have to fight our way through the ooze to that magical nodule.
Delwath: It probably has like basically infinite hit points.
DM: The nodule or this thing?
Delwath: Yeah, the nodule. We probably have to find the nodule.
Wellby: [coughs] Uh, c- uh, can Arrow discover the nodule?
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, I think we should stop here though, because it's 4:15.
DM: We could take a few minutes to do a little bit of dinner prep and then go see the sunset.
Unknown: Sounds good.
DM: Yeah. 'Cause I don't wanna like just...
DM: I mean, you're gonna roll initiative as the first thing we do.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: I don't wanna just start-
Kenzo: Totally, totally, totally.
Seeker: How are we gonna fight something so large?
Seeker: This is ridiculous. I like it.
Delwath: I, I suspect our strategy has gotta be, it probably has effectively unlimited hit points.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So I doubt it's mechanically useful to just try and like kill the various little bits, right?
Delwath: We probably have to get to the,
Unknown: the-
Seeker: So as leviathans, we can swim through it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I guess.
DM: [clears throat] I mean...
Unknown: Is the n- is the nodule thing-
Unknown: It's ooze. We're water
Wellby: ... like we could, I don't know, force cage it and then-
Unknown: The nodule?
Wellby: ... with ourselves on the inside with the nodule to keep the rest of the leviathan out maybe?
Unknown: How far down is the nodule?
DM: I mean-
Unknown: Through the rest of the ooze
DM: ... it's,
DM: it's like in the middle, like it's in the middle of this bubbling mass of ooze, right?
Kenzo: Of, it's in the middle of this?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: This thing.
Kenzo: I, I, I think, I think we might just have to like do like a couple thousand points of damage.
Delwath: Well, I think, I think Seeker and I as leviathans should like head towards the nodule.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: Right?
Kenzo: I mean, sure. I can g- I can join you guys.
Kenzo: I'm an astral being.
Wellby: I can hang out at a safe distance [laughs].
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: You'll soak up the damage [laughs].
Unknown: Oh my God. Just soak up the damage.
Kenzo: Yeah. You stay, you stay up top.
Unknown: I'll take, I'll take the hits. I'll take the hits.
Kenzo: You, you shoot some arrows.
Kenzo: Yeah, just hit some arrows.
Seeker: [laughs] You're our tank today.
Delwath: Like, that seems like maybe the right move, is to try and move through the mass towards the nodule.
Seeker: But, um, what are we gonna do to the nodule once we find it?
Seeker: I don't know if this is cooperative activity.
Unknown: Well, I guess we'll decide when we get there.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Force cage?